[{"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC?", "answers": ["Company ABC makes it easy to find out basic company information by simply browsing their website. You can also search employee reviews to learn about experiences interviewing and working there. Share a few of the facts you learned from researching the company.", "\"I was impressed by the variety of services you offer your customers, and the mission statement at Company ABC. I found the mobile app extremely user-friendly, and I like the new features that help customers save money.\"", "\"I've read great things about working there and I'm excited for the opportunity to work in such a fun environment.Your employee reviews are strong and I understand that you spend a lot of time with community outreach programs.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "In your opinion, what are the benefits of banking with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be assured that you have done your research on Company ABC. Review their website to find out more about their products and services.", "\"I always have a great experience whenever I visit one of your branches. As a customer of Company ABC I am impressed by the consistency and care of the bank tellers. I also love how easy it is to access my account online and make updates to my credit card whenever I travel. The level of service that is demonstrated in Company ABC values is evident.\"", "\"After researching Company ABC products, and what your customers are saying, I believe that the benefits of banking with Company ABC include low fees, no fuss banking, and no sales pitches. Your organization is genuine and has an interest far beyond the bottom line.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about your cash handling experience.", "answers": ["Share some of the details of your experience in cash handling, which are relevant to the position.", "\"As a bank teller, I have handled cash as a part of customer transactions for the past two years. I am experienced with deposits, savings withdrawals, cashing checks and issuing traveler's checks.  I am excited to learn more about Company ABC cash handling procedures.\"", "\"The majority of my cash handling experience includes my time in retail. I was a cashier at Store ABC for three years. As far as the banking industry goes, I have some experience in handling cash from my three months with Bank XYZ.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How do you stay organized?", "answers": ["Staying organized is essential to make sure that you are thorough and pay attention to details, to keep customers happy. It is also necessary for accomplishing your daily tasks behind the scenes. Share a few tools that have helped you stay on-task and on-time.", "\"I prioritize my workload against deadlines to stay organized, always putting the needs of customers first.\"", "\"I work closely with my peers to share responsibilities and ensure key tasks are delegated out, should there be an important deadline to consider.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Why do you want to pursue a career in the banking industry?", "answers": ["Before your interview, take some time to think through your career goals. Company ABC is looking for motivated individuals who want to grow within the company. Share your career plans. Talk about how this position will help you achieve your goals!", "\"I am passionate about the field of finance and accounting, mixed with an unwavering passion for quality customer service. The banking industry allows me to tap into both areas and have a lot of fun making positive customer experiences along the way.\"", "\"Careers in banking run in my family! My mother was a banker and my father, a financial advisor when I was growing up. It always fascinated me how smart they both were. It's in my blood!\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How do you check your work for accuracy?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you are detail oriented when it comes to checking your work. Explain the steps you take to eliminate minor mistakes and ensure your customer transactions and paperwork are accurate.", "\"I take pride in any work with my name attached to it and therefore, always review my work before I submit it. Whether I am typing an email or handling cash, I always check my work twice and sometimes even ask a co-worker to review it first. Being detail oriented and thorough are two of my greatest skill sets.\"", "\"I proof my work before sending it out, and I double check everything. I'll use a calculator when necessary, and ask for help if I am unsure of my own accuracy.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "What are your top three strengths? How will you use them to make an impact at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Reviewing the job description and the company website will give you some direction on which qualities Company ABC values most. Share your most valuable strengths. Think about them within the context of the position. You can refer to the list of responsibilities within the job description as a guide. Explain how your strengths will help you to accomplish these tasks; and better yet, help you to exceed expectations.", "\"I have exceptional attention to detail and great communication skills. I am also quick to solve problems, which helps me handle customer issues with ease. These strengths will help me to build relationships and maintain customer satisfaction.\"", "\"I plan to make an impact at Company ABC through my strong customer service skills, my excellent negotiation skills, and my ability to call on referrals for new business.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about your education. How has it prepared you for this opportunity with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Share some of the highlights from any of your relevant courses from high school, college, university or on the job training. Explain how your experiences will enhance your performance.", "\"Getting a Bachelor's Degree in Business Finance was a great experience. I especially enjoyed my accounting courses because they challenged me to think more critically and furthered my analytical skills. I know these skills will help me to handle work at Company ABC and advise clients on important financial decisions.\"", "\"The bulk of my education has been on-the-job training with my current company. They value continued education and have a tuition reimbursement program which I am happy to have taken advantage of. This year I have taken additional courses in calculus, negotiations, and building a sales pipeline. All of these courses will help me in this role with Company ABC because you are customer service focused while also needing employees who understand banking related concepts and calculations.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "In the banking industry, customer service is essential. Give me an example of a time when you provided excellent customer service.", "answers": ["Think about what customer service means to you. Making the customer happy and receiving positive feedback are great examples! Company ABC wants to hear that you treat customers with respect and are careful to resolve issues. Explain some of the elements of customer service that you possess, like empathy and patience.", "\"I was working as a bank teller when a woman came in, upset about her account. I could tell she needed to vent and I wasn't quite sure what the actual problem was, so I listened first. Then I asked questions to figure out what was going on. She was so appreciative of me because I was able to think on my feet and troubleshoot to solve the problem quickly. She even apologized for raising her voice and thanked me for my patience.\"", "\"In my current position as a bank teller, customers are encouraged to provide feedback via a survey app, after each in-branch visit. For the past three months, I have received the highest ranking for overall customer satisfaction. Delivering excellent customer service is a must for me, and I look forward to bringing this level of service to the customers at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How would you deal with an irate customer?", "answers": ["In the banking industry, keeping customers calm is a much-needed skill. This is where your relaxed demeanor and ability to empathize will come in handy. Company ABC wants to hear about a situation where you used your customer service skills to handle an angry customer.", "\"I had a customer complain about having to wait in line for so long on a busy Monday morning. She was so upset because now she was late for work and the rest of her schedule for the day was thrown off. I listened and let her know I understood where she was coming from, ensuring her I would move as quickly as I could to complete her transaction. Listening and empathizing helped her to calm down and ease the tension.\"", "\"If I were faced with an irate customer I would spend my time listening to their concerns. Usually, people just want to be heard. If things escalated to the point where the customer became threatening, I would call in a supervisor or security.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell us how you keep your knowledge current with ongoing changes in the banking industry.", "answers": ["Due to the competition within the banking industry, Company ABC strives to stay relevant by adapting their products and services to meet customer needs. Consider reading some news articles, press releases, or blogs, to learn more about the industry.", "\"I am interested in learning about helping my customers with their investments. I like to read financial blogs to stay on the cutting edge of latest trends. I also enjoy reading the latest books with a financial scope and listening to financial advice. I also follow Company ABC on Twitter and keep abreast of relative headlines.\"", "\"I am an avid reader, and my top go-to books for banking related knowledge are A, B, and C. I also listen to a few investment-related podcasts on a weekly basis. I understand the importance of staying on top of the latest trends and news in the banking industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about a goal you achieved. What steps did you take to get there?", "answers": ["The banking industry offers a variety of opportunities to those who are motivated. Company ABC is seeking individuals who think about the future and aspire to be successful in everything they do. Think about something you accomplished through hard work and dedication.", "\"Early in my career, I strived to get to know the banking and thrifts systems from a 360-degree view.  I worked hard to partner with my peers in learning how their roles contributed to the whole organizational flow.  I set a goal to become head teller within the first five years of working in this industry.  I hope to continue that career path with Company ABC and am excited for the opportunity to do so.\"", "\"A few years ago I set the goal to complete my Bachelor's in Finance while working full time. I achieved this in just four years, through spending a lot of time in online studies, between working as a bank teller. I am very proud of the discipline and dedication I was able to put towards this goal.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Out of all of our products at Company ABC, which one would you be most likely to use? Why?", "answers": ["Learn as much as you can about what makes Company ABC stand out above other financial institutions. Their reputation is their customer service. They offer a comprehensive spectrum of financial products, so if you are interested in investments, find out more about what they offer. Knowledge is power! It will impress your interviewer and give you an advantage in the interview process!", "\"I would be interested in opening a savings account through Company ABC. I want to buy a house in the next two years, and I would greatly benefit from talking to one of your financial advisors about it. It's nice to know that I can do my banking, investing, and get a loan in the same place that offers the support I will need to make those big decisions!\"", "\"Of all your products, I would be most likely to open a mortgage with Company ABC because your rates are incredible and you make the rules surrounding lending easy to understand.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Give me an example of how you keep track of details while engaging in conversation.", "answers": ["Multi-tasking is a great skill to have within the banking industry. Share a situation that demonstrates your ability to handle the daily tasks of a busy banking environment.", "\"A customer came into the branch with multiple requests. To ensure that I addressed each of their needs, I wrote down a few notes for myself to gather the information. This was also helpful because when I needed to answer the phone in the middle of the transaction, I didn't forget any of the important details and I was able to resolve both requests promptly.  All the while, I kept the customer engaged and made sure their banking experience was enjoyable.\"", "\"To keep track of transaction details, while engaging in conversation, I will ask the customer questions or repeat what they are saying to me. This helps me to commit their needs to memory while still appearing engaged, and in the moment.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about a time when you demonstrated you were trustworthy.", "answers": ["To show Company ABC that you are reliable share an example from your work experience that is relevant to the position.", "\"In my last role, I was responsible for reconciling the banking at the end of the day. Last month, there was an overage, and I demonstrated my true character by reporting this to the management. Together, we partnered to research where this happened and collaborated to coach the team member who caused the error. We adjusted the accounts accordingly.\"", "\"Every successful day in the banking industry is an opportunity to show that I am trustworthy. In my five years within banking, I have never been involved in a discrepancy.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "What do you want to accomplish at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Set some goals so that you can share how this position at Company ABC will help you to achieve them and how you will add value to Company ABC along the way.", "\"First and foremost, I want to deliver top quality service to customers of Company ABC and perform my responsibilities with best in class service.  I want to work at Company ABC because I want to become a financial advisor. Starting out as a professional banker will give me valuable experience resolving client account issues and providing financial assistance, from investments to savings and travel advice.\"", "\"My primary goal is to achieve a leadership position within the banking industry. To do this, I will continue my related education and take any training opportunities that come my way.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about your experience in the banking industry.", "answers": ["Share details of your banking experience to show Company ABC you have what it takes to be successful in the field!", "\"When I worked as a bank teller, I learned how to deal with difficult customers and handle a variety of transactions, from ordering foreign money for travel to removing overdraft fees and educating customers on our products. I used my careful attention to detail to keep my drawer balanced and manage my daily tasks without error.\"", "\"I have 12 years of experience in the banking industry, first as an administrative assistant, then a bank teller, and now; a financial advisor. I have learned a great deal along the way and look forward to putting my experience to work for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How would you respond to a customer complaint?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to be assured that you can professionally handle customer complaints. Give an example of a time you helped resolve a customer's issue.", "\"A customer called me very frustrated about an issue with their bank account. I listened and told them I would be happy to help. I asked more questions to understand the problem and then suggested once I had a better idea of what might solve it. The customer was very relieved and grateful that I took the time to listen and make sense of the issue. I plan to provide consistent customer service in the same way when I work for Company ABC.\"", "\"Each customer complaint is unique; however, I have been trained to handle them all with the same method. Listen, be empathetic, and use phrases such as 'If I understand your concern...' and repeat their words back to them. This method has always worked for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "The banking industry can be stressful. Tell me about a time when you worked in a high-pressure situation.", "answers": ["While working at Company ABC you might find yourself stressed by customers or the fast pace of the work environment. Think of a time where you produced your best work under pressure to showcase how you shine under high-pressure situations.", "\"When I was working as an administrator at a financial firm, I worked in a very high-pressure environment. There was one case that was highly sensitive and required me to pay extra attention to detail. I had limited time to prepare the paperwork, but I was still able to support the lawyer and the client, by staying calm and carefully providing everything they needed. I asked questions to clarify the deadlines that needed to be met and set daily goals to meet them.\"", "\"Almost every day in my banking career has been filled with high-pressure situations. When I am faced with a stressful situation, I remind myself to slow down, breathe, and assess the situation before jumping in with both feet. Customers seem always to appreciate my calm and methodical approach.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "What is the greatest challenge you have faced in your career so far? How did you overcome it?", "answers": ["Consider sharing a professional challenge or a situation you overcame in school. Company ABC wants to hear about the situation and the action you took. Interviewers also want to hear about results. Give an example that demonstrates your perseverance and proactive approach to facing a challenge or conflict.", "\"When I was working for my last company, we had a drastic shift in leadership that required the organization to adapt quickly to new ways of doing things.  This required me to tap into my ability to lead change management for my work and my team. To make this process smoother, I scheduled frequent updates with my team, peers, and leadership to ensure all deliverables were being met on time and the transition to new processes was being handled with the utmost professionalism not to impact the level of service our clients received.  It was a great learning experience for me and the entire organization.\"", "\"The greatest challenge I have faced in my career was the culture of nepotism in my previous position. It is very challenging to overcome morality based difficulties in the workplace while maintaining a positive attitude and keeping motivated. I overcame these feelings by getting to know my co-workers on a more personal level. Making strong connections with others, who were facing the same difficulties as I was, was very helpful.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How do you work in environments with people who are different from you?", "answers": ["The banking industry thrives on team players with communication and listening skills who can help build internal and customer relations with individuals of diverse backgrounds. Give an example of how you led a team, or collaborated with a group for a school project, to show Company ABC that you are perceptive and sensitive to the needs of others.", "\"I have worked with people from all backgrounds and personalities. Whenever I join a new team, I make a point to get to know each person and find ways we can connect. I'm outgoing and friendly with everyone I meet while respecting their different styles and any open ideas they may bring to the team.\"", "\"Diversity is all around us, whether it be at work or home. I treat everyone equally and give everyone the respect and positive attitude that I would expect to receive from them.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Describe a difficult problem and how you approached it.", "answers": ["Interviewers at Company ABC like to see employees coming up with creative solutions. Problem-solving skills are highly regarded within the banking industry.  Use an example that explains the complexity of the situation. You can also use the job description as a guide for some of the challenges you could encounter in this new role. Try to keep it relevant and relatable to the position.", "\"I took a client call that had a history of poor customer experiences with the organization.  One after another, the customer was left frustrated on our banking processes and voiced their concerns in a manner that was unpleasant.  I took the initiative to listen and understand their frustrations, then partnered with the different departments in the company to resolve the concerns and save the customer relationship.\"", "\"While attending university, I was assigned a group project with a group of less than motivated individuals. My grades and performance were significant to me, so I approached the group with a leadership and mentorship mentality. I uncovered what motivated everyone on the team and took the initiative where others would not.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "What interests you about this position?", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC wants to learn more about how your educational or professional background led you to apply for this position. Share what you are most looking forward to about the role and how it relates to your previous experience or future goals.", "\"I enjoy problem-solving and helping people. I worked as a customer service representative in a call center for Wells Fargo when I was in college, and the experience motivated me to learn more about how to help my clients by understanding more about investing, saving, and using banking services to meet their needs. I think working as a personal banker will give me a great foundation to start my career within the banking industry.\"", "\"It is both the job description and the idea of working for Company ABC that has piqued my interest. This role offers the growth and advancement that I have desired for some time now. I especially like that in this position, I would be responsible for A, B, and C. I am ready for those responsibilities in my next position.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How do you respond to problems that require a quick solution?", "answers": ["You may experience a variety of issues related to customers or technical issues while working in the banking industry. Give an example that demonstrates your confidence and your strength as a decision maker and a problem-solver.", "\"I can think quickly and can do mental math, problem-solve, and mention other products and services to offer the customers. In the case of an urgent matter, I trust my instincts and can quickly evaluate situations to recognize the next steps and act accordingly. I feel secure in my ability to think and act quickly while I'm working in ABC position for Company ABC.\"", "\"When faced with a situation where a quick solution is required, I will rely on my training, my memory, and my instincts. I am confident in my ability to find a solution to last minute, or unexpected, problems.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about your favorite manager. What did you enjoy most about working with them?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to hear what excites you and keeps you motivated in a co-working relationship with your boss. They are interested in your values and want to hear about your experience developing relationships with managers.", "\"I love my current boss because she leads with a collaborative and team-oriented style. We have regular team huddles to provide ongoing communication about process changes or upcoming events.\"", "\"My favorite manager was my very first manager when I worked at Company X. She was attentive and spent a lot of time mentoring me. I feel that many of my positive work-based skills and qualities are because of how she interacted with and trained me.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["Think about your definition of success. Be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role with Company ABC.", "\"I define success through my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"For me, success is achieved when I can be proud of what I have accomplished in the day, and can also be proud of the attitude that I kept while meeting those accomplishments.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Tell me about a time when you showed integrity in your work.", "answers": ["Integrity is best displayed through honesty and consistent moral values. The banking industry relies on employees who are trustworthy and reliable. Give an example that shows how you have demonstrated these qualities in the past.", "\"In my last position, I was responsible for the cash deposit on a daily basis. There was never a discrepancy, in the four years that I worked there. I have proven myself reliable through my consistency, always showing up on time, meeting deadlines, and keeping my word.\"", "\"I show integrity in my work in everything that I do. It's important to me that my employer and colleagues see me as trustworthy, with a strong moral compass.\""]}, {"topic": "Banks+and+Thrifts", "question": "Where do you see yourself in five years?", "answers": ["If you are a recent college graduate or starting a new career, you may or may not know where you'd like to be in five years. Company ABC wants to see that you think about the future and are actively working towards your goals. Better yet, they want to know how working for them will help you accomplish your goals! Share how this job will help you get one step closer to achieving your goals.", "\"I plan to continue working in the banking industry as a branch manager, working my way up through attending training and participating in your leadership development program. I am excited to start out in ABC position because I am confident that it will help me achieve my goal and broaden my skill set.\"", "\"Being in a leadership role is important to me, so I plan to be working in a management based position at Company ABC in the future. I will achieve this through continued education and leadership training while also proving my value to you through my everyday work ethic.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "How do you feel about credit cards?", "answers": ["Billions of people worldwide lean on credit cards for purchases every day. The interviewer would like to know that you have an appreciation for the service, but that you are also conscious of the fact that some people have a love/hate relationship with their credit cards! Discuss your thoughts on credit cards, why they are necessary, and why it is essential to maintain a healthy relationship with them. Mainly, the interviewer wants to see that you can sell credit card services without hesitation.", "\"I understand that it is easy to get into trouble with credit cards; however, when used as intended, they are great for a variety of reasons. These reasons include their ability to help people boost their credit scores and credit history. They can be an invaluable source of funds in an emergency. Also, there are great rewards that people can pick up, including flight rewards or cash back.\"", "\"I love using my credit card to gain flight rewards. I use it for everything, and then pay it off before the end of every month. When we use credit cards as intended, they are great! They are easy to abuse; however, so I believe it's imperative for every credit card customer to be smart with their monthly repayment plans.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Company ABC gives priority to bilingual candidates. Do you speak multiple languages?", "answers": ["Your response will be pretty basic considering you either do or don't, speak multiple languages. What is important here is that you express your ability to learn other languages, or you take the time to overcome this lack of skill by showing that you are highly skilled in other areas.", "\"I am fluent in English and a beginner in Spanish. I am certainly willing to dive deeper into learning a new language as I see how it would be valuable in this role. What makes me most qualified for this position is my experience in the credit card services realm; working for your competitor in a call center environment for the past three years.\"", "\"Yes, I speak English and Spanish fluently and have beginner skills in Mandarin. It was important to my parents that I am bilingual, considering the diversity present in our country. I look forward to putting my linguistic skills to work for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "How has your education prepared you for success in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how your education has prepared you for this job with Company ABC. A few highlights you can focus on are some of the relevant financial or sales topics you learned about while attending post-secondary studies. If you have experience working on group projects, share how you improved your listening and communication skills when working with a team.\n\nWhile attending post-secondary studies, you likely learned some core skills that would be transferable to any position. Think about what you learned at your highest levels of education and how that knowledge applies to this job. \n\nSome of these skills could include: \n\n- Time Management\n- Creative Thinking \n- Proposal Writing\n- Public Speaking\n- Presentation Building\n- Independent Learning\n- Academic Research\n- Self-Motivation", "\"My degree in business administration will help me to be successful with Company ABC in a few ways. First, your job posting mentions looking for team members who are accountable, comfortable with cold-calling, and solid researchers. Not only did my degree give me fundamentals of sales, but I also learned how to be more confident when reading people, and how to stand behind my work when it came to assignments and research papers. These are just a few of the ways that my education will help me to succeed in this position.\"", "\"During high school, I had the option to take Marketing classes. I loved these classes, and they taught me about sales, customer service, and the psychology behind a sale. This knowledge will be helpful as I discuss credit card options with Company ABC customers. I look forward to taking what I know and expanding on that during my new hire training.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "How comfortable are you selling products to Company ABC clients?", "answers": ["Working with Company ABC means that you should be comfortable talking to customers about the variety of products available to them. If you have sales training and previous experience, the chances are that you will have a solid understanding that this role comes with targets and goals. If you have little work experience, it is okay to ask the interviewer for more detail on what the expectations will be in this role.", "\"I have many years' experience selling a variety of products; both services based and digital and am very comfortable working with customers to uncover their needs as they are related to Company ABC products. Once my product training is complete, I am 100% comfortable in selling and cross-selling your valuable products to deserving customers.\"", "\"I understand that Company ABC offers an excellent training program. Once I have completed my on-the-job training here, I am confident that I will be ready and very comfortable is selling your products to your valued clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What would make you lose your patience with a Company ABC customer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see professionalism, poise, and self-control from you; even during the most challenging customer-facing situations. Of course, you would never lose your temper with a customer - a point that you need to make very clear when you respond. Share how you keep your composure, even during the most challenging situations.", "\"If I feel that my patience level with a client is reaching a breaking point, I will make some reason to have to exit the conversation and revisit it after a short break. For example, I would say that I must attend a meeting and that I would call them back in 20 minutes. Then, I would take the time to breathe and compose myself. Also, I would take the time to think of a better approach. Rest assured, I will always remain professional and keep my composure.\"", "\"I have witnessed people lose their patience on the job, and it's a very unprofessional situation to experience. I am not a fan of people who interrupt and are aggressive so, if I were on the phone or in-person with a customer like this, I would not engage in their behavior; rather, ask them to calm down. If needed, I would escalate the situation to my supervisor.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Would you break Company ABC policy to satisfy a customer?", "answers": ["Company ABC has firm policies in place for many reasons. In the world of finance and credit card services, it's crucial that you follow the guidelines given to you, should you be hired. Some of these guidelines are not only coming from Company ABC, but from the government and various finance and credit laws. \n\nIt's important to note that bending the rules CAN be acceptable, should there be a collective agreement with your supervisor ahead of time. Discuss how you would work around satisfying a customer despite restrictions in policy.", "\"If it were evident that bending a policy was the only option to satisfy a customer, I would escalate the issue to my direct supervisor to see what I can do. Customer service is an incredibly important factor in the continued success of Company ABC and I am confident that a workaround is often possible. With that said, I do not believe it is my place to make a call like that all on my own. I will always consult a superior, first.\"", "\"It's essential to be flexible whenever possible, but not when it means harming the company or breaking important policy. Certain policies do not necessarily work for some customers, as they do for others. I understand that Company ABC recognizes this need for flex, which is why you offer wiggle room whenever possible. If faced with this type of situation, I would, of course, ask for assistance before deciding to break company policy.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you believe that your co-workers and clients see you as an honest and trustworthy person?", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like to know if you are self-aware; recognizing how people see you in the workplace. It's one thing to say that you are an honest and trustworthy person, but it's best if you can support your answer with a real-life example of a time when you acted with integrity. This question is a great time to offer up your references as well.", "\"Honest and trustworthy are two words that you will certainly hear from my supervisor when you call for a reference. For me, these are fundamental values. You can rest assured that I will always act with integrity, with clients and co-workers. During my 15-year career in the finance industry, there has never been a discrepancy in my work.\"", "\"While attending post-secondary studies, many of my fellow students complimented me on my integrity while working on group projects. I am reliable and very prepared. You can count on me, to be honest with your clients and you can depend on me to do what's right; even when nobody is looking.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Walk me through your experience, managing an end-to-end sales cycle.", "answers": ["An end-to-end sales cycle has a variety of stages, including: \n\n- Prospecting\n- Approaching \n- Negotiating\n- Fulfilling \n- Following Up \n\nIf you are working on an end-to-end sales cycle, you are responsible for finding and contacting the customer, working with them until the sale is complete, and then following up with them; continuing to nurture the sale long after the contracts are signed, or payment is made. \n\nWalk the interviewer though any experience that you have when it comes to handling an end-to-end sales cycle. If you do have this experience, you could choose to talk about what you learned during your post-secondary studies when it came to the cycle of major assignments, for instance.", "\"In my current position, I am responsible for prospecting, cold calling, negotiating, collecting payment, and follow up after the sale. I thoroughly enjoy being responsible for every aspect of the sale because I am the only one accountable for my results. I am competitive with myself, and so this type of sales cycle speaks to that competitive side.\"", "\"I am new to my career, so the best example of end-to-end management would be more on the project management side, from my time in post-secondary. I have been responsible for taking care of self-led and group-based projects in university. To ensure success, I keep organized with the use of a project management app called Monday, where I can keep everything in one place, while also receiving notifications and alerts when deadlines are coming up, or I need to take action.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Company ABC has a variety of goals and KPIs for each employee. How do you go about meeting and exceeding your goals every month?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know your approach to ensuring success in the workplace. It's essential that you give the nod to the fact that Company ABC has goals and KPIs waiting for you, should you be the successful candidate. \n\nThe hiring authority would like to hear that you are great with goal setting and organizing your day. When you have a great plan in place, this makes it much easier to meet and exceed your goals. If you have an example of a time when you recently exceeded your goals at work, talk about what you did to get there!", "\"I have met my goals for the past six months straight. When I first started in the role, I struggled with meeting the many targets placed out for me. Once I realized that by breaking all expectations down into a daily view, rather than a monthly view, I was able to thrive. By doing so, I could break down my tasks into hours while making mini expectations for myself.\"", "\"I learned about goal setting and the importance of timing in goal setting, while in university. Often, I would have many assignments due at one time. To ensure that I was never confused or delivered a late project, I kept a color-coded iCal that I would refer to for everything that came up. I think that meeting and exceeding my goals and KPIs at Company ABC will require the same level of organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you have sales targets in your current role? How is your performance measured?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about how your success is currently measured. How do you know that you are doing a great job? If you have targets, goals, and metrics in your current position, this question should be straightforward for you to answer. \n\nHiring authorities love to hear numbers and percentages since they make your experience easy to relate to and understand. If you did not have sales targets in your last role, discuss the measurements addressed in your performance reviews. If you do not have performance reviews, have you received praise for a job well done?", "\"I have a variety of targets in my current position, including average sale per customer, add-on or cross-sale value, call time, and customer satisfaction ratings. My performance is measured using a blend of all these factors. We are asked to review our own performance daily, ensuring that we are always on target. It's a high-pressure sales environment; however, I am a competitive person, so I enjoy the pace. I look forward to learning more about your targets here at Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I have not worked in a role with specific targets, I am aware of the importance of goal setting in the credit card services industry. Currently, my performance is measured by customer feedback and reviews. I have been the recipient of many happy customer reviews, which makes me very proud. I am eager to learn more about your sales targets at Company ABC. \""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Tell me about the last time you handled a demanding customer. What did you do well, and what could you have done better?", "answers": ["Every customer-based interaction is different, and the hiring authority would like to see that you can handle any situation that comes your way. If you have some work experience, you have likely come across a demanding customer in the past. Tell a brief story that outlines the challenge, the action that you took, and include the positive result of your actions. \n\nIf you are new to your career, think about a time when you had a problematic professor or had to collaborate on a group project with another student who didn't work positively with you.", "\"I have difficult customers a few times a week, considering the call-center environment where I currently work focus' primarily on customers with accounts in arrears. The last situation I recall was a woman who was claiming that around $5,000 in credit card charges were not hers. The issue was that the charges were from places where she shopped regularly. Rather than telling her that we knew her claim to be untrue, I offered a very tempting re-payment plan with late fees waived. She ended up taking the offer, which was great for both parties. If I had this situation again, I would take more time to work with the client to ensure that they did not get themselves into a sticky credit situation again. I believe a large part of my job should include educating our credit clients.\"", "\"As a recent business graduate, I had had some professors who were very challenging when it came down to their communication skills. One professor was brief when it came to expectations and deadlines. I decided to approach her and ask for more precise guidelines. She was offended and not much help. I am happy that I asked for help, but I could have approached her differently. What I learned was that not everyone communicates as well as I do, and it's crucial that I find clarification on my own rather than expect others to fill in the blanks for me. As challenging as this situation was, it was also a valuable learning experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you prefer to work for Company ABC in a B2B or a B2C approach?", "answers": ["Company ABC will have opportunities present in both business-to-business and business-to-consumer divisions. Before your interview, it is crucial that you research the opportunities available in both divisions. Of course, you want your response to be a match for the position to which you are interviewing. With that said, there will always be an opportunity to grow and be promoted over time. Be honest with the interviewer about your preference, if you have one, but also be sure to express a desire to focus on the position at hand.", "\"The role at Company ABC that initially piqued my interest is a B2B opportunity; a division where I am most experienced. When I initially started my career, I worked in a B2C environment, which I quite enjoyed. I do; however, prefer to work with businesses at this stage in my career. My preference comes from my appreciation for the process, the longer sales cycle, and the interaction with corporate decision makers.\"", "\"Being new to my career, I feel that working in a B2C environment will be the best start for me. I am eager to work with smaller accounts with more personal needs. I do appreciate; however, that there will be an opportunity for me to prove myself within Company ABC and work my way into a B2B position down the road.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you have experience using a CRM tool such as Salesforce?", "answers": ["Think of the software and programs that you have used in your current and previous roles. Be prepared to discuss the programs that you are most experienced with, being sure to highlight any programs used at Company ABC. \n\nPopular CRM's include: \n\n- Salesforce\n- Oracle \n- NetSuite\n- Microsoft Dynamics", "\"My CRM experience is primarily with Salesforce and Oracle. The companies I have worked for have all been enterprise-level organizations, requiring robust CRMs with many tracking tools. Do you use Salesforce here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am tech savvy and confident in my ability to learn any CRM that you use here. If you'd like, I would be happy to take some online training and watch tutorials, to get a head start on the CRM you use here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Confidentiality is of the utmost importance to us. Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement? Under what circumstance would you breach a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Company ABC works with, and keeps, a great deal of sensitive information on their clients such as credit and banking information. For this reason, they will have confidentiality agreements for you to sign as an employee. These confidentiality agreements could also cover trade secrets, sales approaches, and client lists. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements and assure them that you would never breach a contract.", "\"I have signed NDA's and various confidentiality agreements in all my previous roles, with no issues. As an employee in the banking and finance industry, I understand the importance of protecting our customers. I hold myself accountable to confidentiality agreements and any other important documentation.\"", "\"Exercising discretion has never been an issue for me, and I am happy to comply with any matters of confidence policied by Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "If you were to accidentally do something wrong at work, what would you do to repair the situation?", "answers": ["When working for Company ABC there are a lot of moving parts to ensure that client files are correct, documentation is accurate, and that employees follow all policies to the letter. \n\nThe interviewer would like to know more about your character, and how you would react if you realized that you did something wrong at work. Of course, the best way to approach this is to show that you would own up to the situation while doing everything required to fix the potential issue. Show the hiring authority that you understand the value of ownership in the workplace.", "\"I dislike making errors in the workplace, which is why I like to keep checklists to ensure that I have followed every procedure as expected. If I accidentally do something wrong at work, I will immediately fix the error and then fill my supervisor in, if required. If the situation were more serious and required an outside department to help, I would call on assistance right away. The longer a problem sits, the worse it can become, so I believe it's best to own up and fix the issue immediately.\"", "\"I am not afraid to ask for help. If I were to do something wrong at work accidentally, I would let my manager know immediately. I would also ask for extra training after the fact, to avoid the situation from happening again. Prevention is key!\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "When is it okay to stretch the truth to make a sale or cross-sell a new product?", "answers": ["The sales process is a significant part of working in credit card services. You will have targets and goals to achieve, which are very important; however, the interviewer needs to know that you will approach your sales goals with the utmost integrity. You already know that it is not okay to lie, or stretch the truth, to make a sale. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to sell with an honest approach.", "\"It is never okay to stretch the truth to make a sale or cross-sell a new product. If I have to stretch the truth, this means that the product I am presenting is not the right fit for the customer. When I keep my customers' needs top of mind, I can make a sale that fits their needs while also meeting my goals and targets.\"", "\"When selling a financial product or service, describing the features and benefits that are relevant to each customer is the best approach to closing the deal. Stretching the truth is never in the best interest of a company or a customer.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Tell me about any formal sales and customer service training you have received.", "answers": ["If you have some years of work experience, you have likely received training in customer service and perhaps sales techniques. If you are new to your career, you may have self-trained by watching YouTube channels dedicated to sales techniques. Or, maybe you spend your time reading books on business, sales, and customer service approaches. \n\nYour formal training could be partaking in an excellent onboarding plan from a former employer, hands-on training, or industry coursework. Be sure to express to the interviewer that you have an interest in continually improving your sales and customer service skills.", "\"Being in the financial industry, I have been lucky to have received a lot of great training through course materials, onboarding programs, and access to online coursework. Topics of this training range from upselling, cross-selling, customer service, dispute management, and ethics. I am well versed in building rapport and asking the right questions to uncover customers' needs.\"", "\"I have taken some Dale Carnegie training and did learn a lot about customer service and basic sales while taking my business degree. I look forward to gaining even more expertise through the training offered here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What does it mean to be a persuasive person? Do you think you are persuasive by nature?", "answers": ["The power of persuasion is essential in sales, customer service, and the finance industry. Keep in mind that being a persuasive person does not mean that you are arrogant, aggressive, or that you spend your time convincing someone to do something that makes them uncomfortable. \n\nAs a finance and credit professional, you use persuasion to pitch and influence. Discuss what you interpret persuasion to be and be sure to address the fact that you are persuasive when necessary.", "\"Persuasion is a big part of sales, but it's all about proper timing. First, I lay down the groundwork and build rapport. I ask questions of my customers to find out more what they need. Once I have built enough evidence that my path is the most beneficial approach for them, I then begin to build a persuasive case.\"", "\"Persuasion is an art form and one that I developed while earning my business degree. I would use persuasion in my papers and writing, helping others to see the upside of my approach.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What tools can Company ABC provide you, so that you can deliver world-class customer service?", "answers": ["If Company ABC hires you, it is in their best interest to provide you with only the best possible tools to make you successful in your new role! There are many tools available to help you succeed, such as excellent training, a robust CRM program, and well-equipped management. Talk to the interviewer about what need to deliver exceptional service to their clients.", "\"I believe that, in the financial and credit card services industry, it is vital for me to have robust tracking and automation tools, to best help my customers. With streamlined processes and organized information, I can better serve those who come to Company ABC for credit card solutions.\"", "\"I am new to my career so, for that reason, the most important tools that Company ABC can provide me include proper training and a knowledgeable management team. I am eager to learn and grow with the full support of an excellent department.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Tell me about your experience in developing key internal relationships with Risk Management, Underwriting, and New Accounts.", "answers": ["With large companies like Company ABC, there will be many internal departments present, and the interviewer would like to know that you have a history of working well cross-departmentally. \n\nIf you come from a financial services background, you probably have experience working with underwriters, sales teams, and others. \n\nIf you are new to the industry, you will want to speak about your experience working with people who have a job function different from yours. \n\nIf you are a recent graduate, talk about your experience developing relationships with other students during group projects, or how you built relationships with your professors and other staff or faculty.", "\"My current company is smaller than Company ABC; however, we do have a variety of departments such as Customer Service, Underwriting, Account Recovery, and more. I create relationships throughout various departments by always being courteous, remembering names, saying thank you when they help me out, and being a respectful co-worker, overall. It's important in the credit card services realm that everyone works together as a unit so that we can service accounts adequately and quickly.\"", "\"Being new to my career, the bulk of my experience with cross-collaboration is with group projects in university, as well as the lasting relationships I built with my school's faculty. One of the keys to these great relationships is the fact that I was always nice, and had a humble approach by asking questions but also being present and ready to learn. I will bring the same attitude to Company ABC, ensuring strong relationships with your other internal departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What does cross-selling mean to you? Tell me two Company ABC products that you could cross-sell.", "answers": ["Cross-selling is when you sell a variety of services or products to an existing customer. The point of cross-selling is to increase the amount of product that each customer accepts or purchases. With a cross-selling plan, companies can increase the value of each existing customer, which is generally easier than gaining new customers. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about what cross-selling means to you. Show that you have done your homework on Company ABC products by discussing what type of 'add-on' you could suggest to an existing customer.", "\"To me, cross-selling means introducing new products to existing customers. I like to cross-sell products that only suit what the customer already has from my company. For instance, if I were working with Company ABC, I would recommend insurance protection as an add-on for every credit-card customer. I would also upsell to a more premium card if they qualified so that they could earn better credit card rewards.\"", "\"Cross-selling, from what I understand, is similar to upselling, where you add on another item when closing a sale. If I were to cross-sell a Company ABC customer, I would suggest one of your protection plans or job-loss insurance to go along with their new credit card.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What do you know about credit card services, and how market conditions impact our business?", "answers": ["If you are already familiar with the credit card services industry, the interviewer will be expecting a response that reflects your work experience and insight. Discuss recent market conditions and how you have seen conditions impact the credit card services business. If you are new to the financial services industry, you will be giving more of an educated guess.", "\"From what I have learned in my years of working in credit card services, the credit market becomes stronger when market conditions are weaker. Higher unemployment rates and lower income often mean a rise in credit card balances, more borrowers, higher interest rates, and more accounts in arrears. Today, more people than ever have credit cards. In the USA alone, nearly 200 million people have credit card balances. Recently we have seen an increase in subprime borrowers, those with credit scores from 580 to 669. This number is a 4%+ increase from last year.\"", "\"I have been reading more about the credit card services industry since applying to this position. What I have learned is that the credit market continues gaining strength. Consumer balances have continued to increase, and delinquency rates have remained constant.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Have you ever worked in a call center environment where your calls are recorded?", "answers": ["This question is straightforward since it's either a yes or a no! With that said, be sure to express the fact that you understand why calls are recorded at Company ABC. This action is not one of mistrust, rather an effort that has to take place to protect the company, its employees, and its customers. You can keep your response brief, and to the point.", "\"I currently work for a competitor of Company ABC where my incoming and outgoing calls are all monitored. Considering the volume of people that I speak with every day, I appreciate the added protection that comes with knowing there is a backup available of my conversations and actions.\"", "\"I have never worked in a call center environment; however, I completely understand why it is important for Company ABC to protect its customers and employees in this manner. I am 100% fine with having my calls recorded in the workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you have strong business and financial acumen?", "answers": ["The hiring authority is looking for a suitable match when it comes to the job requirements and your skill level. To showcase your business and financial acumen, you can: \n\n- Refer to your post-secondary education \n- Discuss how you remain in-the-know on essential business topics\n- Talk about how your current job keeps you sharp in this industry \n\nOutline what makes you savvy in the business and financial industry, while also expressing to the interviewer that you have an interest in continued learning and growth.", "\"I consider my business and financial acumen to be an intermediate level. I have worked in the financial services industry for eight years and lean on my education in Investment Analysis to make sound decisions on the job. I continue to learn and grow by reading books on money management and risk assessment. I am eager to gain even more expertise through exceptional training at Company ABC.\"", "\"As a recent graduate in Finance with a focus on Risk Assessment, I believe that I have more than just the basics in business and finance. My education will give me an excellent foundational start for this role with Company ABC. Although my work experience is limited, my knowledge is strong, fresh, and current, and I am eager to learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "What is the most helpful piece of customer feedback you have received lately?", "answers": ["Feedback is valuable in the workplace and, when it comes directly from customers, this is a prime opportunity for you to learn and grow. The hiring authority wants to see that you are open to feedback and that you take action when you receive it. Discuss one piece of helpful feedback, either formal or informal, that you have received from a customer as of late. If you are new to your career, you can refer to an example from your post-secondary career or volunteer work.", "\"I recently had a customer comment that I spoke too quickly for them to understand what I was saying fully. When I get into a groove, I know that I can speed up my work and speech, so I did appreciate the fact that the customer brought it to my attention. I have started to record myself with my sales scripts, practicing 30 minutes per day, with a focus on slowing down.\"", "\"The most helpful feedback that I received lately came from my professor in one of my business classes. He asked me to dig a bit deeper and start tackling topics in my papers that were not in my wheelhouse. He wanted me to stretch myself further. I agreed and wrote my last paper on a topic entirely new to me. This suggestion was great because it forced me out of my comfort zone and challenged my research and writing skills at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Company ABC does a complete background check on all candidates, including a credit check. Do you have strong credit and a clean criminal record?", "answers": ["Most companies in the financial and credit card services industry will require strong credit from their employees. Also, a clean criminal record is a must. As an employee of Company ABC you will be privy to a lot of sensitive information so you must be trusted. You must answer this question truthfully and with full disclosure.", "\"I have a clean criminal record and believe that my credit score is above average. I have been working hard to build my credit score over the past few years. I am willing to comply with any background check that you require of me.\"", "\"My criminal record is clean; however, when it comes to my credit, I do not have a lot of history. What I do have is positive, but I am currently working to build my history further.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Which influencer do you appreciate the most, in the financial realm? What is it that you like about their approach to finance-related topics?", "answers": ["Every industry is all about influencers and thought leaders today! The interviewer wants to see that you are in-the-know when it comes to the conversations happening in your industry. Name someone in the finance realm that you listen to, gain advice from, and admire. Since this is an open-ended question, beware of keeping your answer brief and to the point by discussing one or two things that you appreciate about their approach or philosophy.", "\"Without a doubt, my favorite person to listen to and learn from in the finance realm is Michelle Singletary. She is a columnist for the Washington Post and the author of 'The 21 Day Financial Fast' which I think everyone should read. I appreciate her practical advice and the fact that she is to-the-point.\"", "\"I like to dive into topics such as economics and financial growth so, for that reason, Mike Quindazzi is my go-to thought leader on these topics. He is a Managing Director for PwC, which gives him a lot of Klout in the industry. I have attended one of his conferences on financial success and follow him on multiple social platforms.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Do you have any credit products with Company ABC? Why or why not?", "answers": ["The interviewer simply wants to know if you bank with them. If you do not, that is okay; you can say that you have been with your current bank for X amount of years and have been loyal. Be sure to express a willingness to try Company ABC products; however! \n\nIf you do bank with Company ABC give a brief list of the products that you use, and what you enjoy most about doing business with them. Either way, keep your response positive.", "\"I am a happy customer of Company ABC! I have two credit cards as well as a savings account with your institution. Because my experience has been so positive, I will be a raving advocate when interacting with your customers.\"", "\"I have banked with a different institution since opening my first ever bank account. With that said, I see the importance of doing business with Company ABC so that I have the first-hand experience when it comes to the processes and services that your customers go through.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Have you considered expanding your education in the credit card or financial services realm?", "answers": ["If your post-secondary education is not related to the credit card or financial services industry, the interviewer may want to see an interest in future growth. Expanding your knowledge could include college or university coursework, on-the-job training, or self-led learning through podcasts or books. \n\nIt's essential that you show an interest in growing your knowledge; thus, helping you to be more successful in this role. Further education will also open up new opportunities for you within the company, earning you promotions!", "\"I am always considering new ways to educate myself in the credit and finance world. In addition to my Bachelor of Finance degree; I continually self-education on trends and topics in the industry, through podcasts and books. I am certainly open to suggestions when it comes to further education options that will help me to succeed and grow with Company ABC.\"", "\"I recently completed my degree in Financial Analysis and would love to learn more about risk assessment in personal banking. If you have recommendations for me, I am all ears!\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Card+Services", "question": "Tell me about the last time you made a product suggestion to a customer that helped them in a big way.", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like to know more about your customer service skills. Walk the interviewer through a brief story of a time that you recently helped a customer by using excellent sales skills, upselling, or even cross-selling skills. It is important to highlight what the customers' need was, how you went about uncovering that need, and how you closed the deal; all with a happy customer, in the end!", "\"I recently had a customer call in because they were having trouble making their credit card payments. I asked a few questions, including how they used their credit card most months, what their biggest concern was, and what they could afford. I ended up downgrading this customer to a simpler credit card with no frills, a lower annual rate, and a 3% lower interest rate. The customer was thrilled and thanked me for being so helpful.\"", "\"I received a customer service call from a client who was upset at their credit card interest rate. I carefully explained that their rate was high because they initially qualified, many years ago, as a subprime customer. I offered to do a new credit check. The customer agreed, and this check showed that the customer had significantly increased their credit score over the past five years. Because of this credit score increase, I was able to offer the customer a much better credit card product with lower interest and a better rewards program. It felt great to help them!\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "What would you do if you caught a co-worker stealing money from Company ABC?", "answers": ["Since you will handle thousands upon thousands of dollars in cash every day, the interviewer wants assurance that you are responsible, keen, and honest. A part of honesty is also holding your co-workers accountable for their actions, and following Company ABC policy. Discuss the steps you would take if you caught a co-worker stealing.", "\"I show pride in my work, and always take concern for the good of the company. I would feel obligated to report a co-worker stealing from the company, whether it was $10 or $10,000. If I were to witness a co-worker stealing, I would report the incident immediately.\"", "\"Theft is never acceptable, no matter the amount of intention. If I witnessed a co-worker stealing money from Company ABC, I would report the incident to my nearest supervisor. Of course, if you have a more formal process for reporting incidents of theft, I would refer to those guidelines.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "How would you approach a task you were not trained to do?", "answers": ["Thinking on your feet is an essential trait in the banking industry. There is a lot to learn and know, and many changes in the day as you help a large variety of customers with varying needs. The interviewer wants to see how you approach a situation when you do not possess the knowledge or training required. \n\nThe key to answering this question is to show that you are competent and able to find answers independently. Perhaps you are an excellent researcher, or maybe you ask others for help, without hesitation. Show the interviewer that you would remain calm and collected; doing what you need to get the job done right.", "\"Going into my last customer service job, I had minimal training on service and the point of sale system. I watched online tutorials from YouTube, asked my colleagues for help, and observed others on the job. If asked to complete a task that I was not trained to do, I would take the same approach. I am highly capable and a good researcher, so I'm confident in my ability to learn independently.\"", "\"When I first started university, I was asked to give a presentation in the first week of my courses. I had never crafted a real presentation before, let alone speak in public, so I was very nervous. I spent an entire afternoon watching TED Talks so that I could get an idea of what makes a good presentation. Then, I brushed up on my PowerPoint skills and made engaging visuals. When I am asked to perform a task outside of my comfort zone, I jump in feet first and learn, using the resources available to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "If hired, how will you begin to build trusting relationships with our clients and your co-workers?", "answers": ["Credit Unions often boast a tighter-knit customer base than traditional banks. Members of Company ABC may have higher expectations when it comes to the level of service they receive from you, and it all begins with connection. With a wide range of backgrounds, and personalities; client and coworker connections can take time to form. Discuss how you ensure an active line of communication right from the start.", "\"First impressions can mean everything, so I will make a strong attempt to build a genuine connection with Company ABC clients and team members. With your members, I can ask lighthearted discovery questions such as where they work, or if they have any fun vacations coming up. I will also be open to feedback on how I can best support them and their banking needs. With my co-workers, I will be there to listen, observe, learn, and support.\"", "\"To build a trusting relationship with my co-workers, I will show up to work on time and dressed appropriately. I will listen to their coaching and ask for feedback. When it comes to the members of Company ABC I will add value to every interaction and get to know them on a level that is personal yet still professional.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "What do you believe we can improve on, at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer is not asking for you to give a whole list of what you think they do poorly. This question offers an opportunity for you to point out a single aspect that you could improve on, should you be hired. The point is to show the interviewer that there may be a gap in their offering that you can help fill. Remain positive and upbeat when you give your answer.", "\"I believe that Company ABC could serve its customers even better by having a stronger online and social media presence for each community that you serve. I happen to be very passionate about marketing, and quite knowledgable so I am happy to help!\"", "\"Although your community involvement is strong, there are opportunities for involvement that would branch out past seasonal volunteer work. I would love to see Company ABC host more community efforts rather than primarily sponsoring the efforts of others. I have an extensive background in volunteering as a volunteer coordinator and could help Company ABC craft a great strategy for this particular community.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Company ABC puts our members first. How will you always put our members' needs first?", "answers": ["Credit union and banking environments are competitive, and one of the factors they compete over is who offers the best customer service! People want to bank where they feel comfortable and welcome. Discuss with the interviewer how you ensure that their members will receive the best service from you, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"My professional approach is always to treat the members of Company ABC how I expect to be treated when I go to my bank. Sometimes, I go to my bank to make a quick deposit and other times; it's to apply for a loan or ask for financial advice. Those visits can feel vulnerable, so it's important that a member feels welcome and comfortable no matter the nature of their visit. I will put your members' needs first by always smiling, being willing to help, and maintaining my knowledge on Company ABC products.\"", "\"I appreciate everything that Company ABC does to put members first. I will put Company ABC members first by maintaining knowledge of your products and services. I will actively listen to each member I serve, and ask them discovery questions, to help me best uncover their needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Customers can become upset with Company ABC policy at times. How would you handle a customer who is angry because they do not agree with a policy?", "answers": ["Part of working in a highly customer-service driven environment is also serving members when they are not happy. The most common complaints in the banking industry surround speed, policy, or unwanted fees. Talk to the interviewer about your approach when it comes to an unhappy customer. \n\nSome critical steps to customer dispute resolution include: \n\n- Remaining kind, polite, and pleasant\n- Actively listen to their grievances \n- Apologizing for the situation \n- Maintaining a neutral tone of voice\n- Not taking anything they say, personally", "\"I have a lot of customer dispute training which has given me some thick skin when it comes to challenging situations. I know that bank policy can seem convoluted at times, difficult to understand, or even frustrating, so I do have empathy for customers who are upset over policy. I take the time to review policy in easy-to-understand language. It's also important that I unpack what their needs are and what is truly concerning the customer. Usually, I can find a solution or at least a work-around that satisfies the customer.\"", "\"If I cannot seem to calm a customer down, due to a policy, I will straight out ask them what I can do, aside from change policy, to make them happy. Often it isn't the policy itself but that the customer feels stuck in some way. When the customer is aware that I am willing to rectify the situation, they are much more likely to level with me.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Are you aware that this job has goals and targets? When have you worked in a similar environment?", "answers": ["Depending on your role with Company ABC you may have business targets such as opening 25 new savings accounts every month or cross-selling a newly rolled out product. \n\nEmployees of Company ABC must be willing to let customers know about the products available to them, including loans and special offers. Show your awareness of these requirements, and that you have performed tasks like this in the past.", "\"Meeting important targets and goals is a large part of my current role. If a customer is missing an important product such as checking, savings, or a credit account, I will let them know about the product and how it benefits their financial goals. I am more than comfortable performing job functions that include targets and goals.\"", "\"I am somewhat competitive, from my time spent in team sports, so the idea of having goals and targets to meet is very enticing to me. I know that the right banking product can make all the difference to a member, so I am happy to make recommendations based on my observations.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Walk me through your customer service training.", "answers": ["A significant part of success in the banking industry comes down to exceptional customer service delivery. This statement is especially true with credit unions who are primarily known for delivering personalized customer service. \n\nWalk the interviewer through any formal training you have received in the area of customer service. Your education could include on-the-job training, online courses, or even books that you have read in your spare time. Show the interviewer that you have an interest in bettering your customer service delivery. This question is a great time to ask the interviewer about their company-specific customer service training and manuals.", "\"I would love to know more about the customer service training that you offer here at Company ABC. I have a great instinct when it comes to delivering the needs of my customers. Being in the banking industry for the last five years, I have absorbed many materials related to customer service. My strengths are in building rapport with clients, remembering their names and interests, and making them feel welcome every time they visit.\"", "\"Being a recent graduate and new to my career, I cannot say that I have received any customer service-specific training.  With that said, I believe my service instinct is strong, and I know what type of service I like to receive from my bank. I would be happy to take any training that you recommend and would love to hear more about your specific training program here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Are you a Company ABC member?", "answers": ["The answer to this question will be straightforward; yes, or no. Depending on your status, you may not be eligible for member approval at Company ABC. If you are not a member, or not eligible to be a member, talk about the fact that you would be a member if possible. If you are a member, be ready to talk about what you enjoy most about banking with Company ABC.", "\"I have been a member at Company ABC since moving to this town in 2011. I have been thrilled with the personalized customer service, your competitive fees, and reasonable interest rates on unsecured loans. Just last year, I received my first mortgage through Company ABC and was so happy with how smooth the entire process was.\"", "\"At this point, I do not meet the requirements to become a member at Company ABC. I would love to be a member one day when I am eligible. I hear many excellent factors associated with membership at your credit union. The online reviews are excellent, and I look forward to further serving your hard-working, well-deserving members.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Credit Unions rank higher in customer service than traditional banks. Why do you think this is?", "answers": ["Your opinion matters! When you are working for a credit union vs. a traditional bank, it's essential that you can wholly appreciate the difference between the two offerings. \n\nDiscuss why you believe credit unions rank higher in customer service over traditional banks. Be sure to compliment Company ABC if you have had an excellent customer service experience with them.", "\"Large banks are for-profit, making them more sales driven. This approach can often mean a lower focus on customer service and impersonal service. When it comes to credit unions, we often have higher community involvement, which translates to better customer service at the same time. Credit unions often have better employee training, which also can mean more personalized service for members.\"", "\"Credit unions are non-profits, and member-owned, which means they will almost always be more customer-centric. Credit unions are often involved in community groups and take more care than large, and traditional banks can. Also, if we consider geographical location; most credit unions are in smaller, rural communities where service and connection is everything.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "In your opinion, what is the best service or product offered at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have put time into researching and getting to know the offering at Company ABC. As a well-established credit union, Company ABC offers an excellent range of banking products for their loyal members. Choose which service or product you think stands out from the rest, and why.", "\"I appreciate the terms surrounding your Traditional Individual Retirement Arrangement (IRA). When used properly, this tax-deferred retirement plan can significantly benefit your members. Could you share with me what percentage of your members take advantage of this offering?\"", "\"The home equity loans offered by Company ABC sound wonderful! Your fixed-rate equity loan offers stability for the members who take advantage. This product is a great option for your members who need money for a one-time or unexpected expense. Set monthly payments mean there are no surprises for your members.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "You will handle member transactions in this role. Talk to me about your mathematical skills.", "answers": ["Expectations are that you handle every member transaction with the utmost care and attention. In addition to this keen sense of detail; strong math skills are also a necessity when it comes to working in a banking environment. Discuss your math skills, showing confidence in your abilities related to cash-handling, counting, and making smooth member transactions.", "\"I did very well in any math-related courses while obtaining my business degree. My math skills are strong, and I very rarely have a discrepancy in the workplace. I will meet the expectations of accuracy for Company ABC and your members.\"", "\"Math has always been a strong suit for me. I did very well in high school math and was even a tutor for struggling students. I am comfortable with the math skills required when it comes to accepting cash, giving exact cash amounts, keying in transactions, balancing cash floats, and performing other banking-related tasks.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "How do you protect the privacy of every customer you assist?", "answers": ["Credit Unions have many systems in place to protect the privacy of their members. These efforts include technology and monitoring techniques, privacy policies, and renowned training for employees. Discuss the ways you will ensure that you respect the steps Company ABC takes to protect their members.", "\"I protect the privacy of every customer I assist by speaking in a respectful volume, protecting passwords, and advising banking customers on how to keep their information safe. These safety efforts include banking in person, at ATM's, and during online banking. Education and knowledge are critical keys to protecting one's privacy.\"", "\"I will protect the privacy of every customer I assist by being aware of my surroundings, keeping a strong password and protecting it, and will never share confidential information. I understand that I will be privy to sensitive and confidential information while working at Company ABC and I'll do everything I can to ensure a members' information is never compromised.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Do you have any sales experience? Would you be comfortable upselling a Company ABC banking product?", "answers": ["In the banking industry, customer service can also mean cross-selling or upselling services that you know will benefit the Company ABC member based on their banking habits. \n\nShow the hiring authority that you would be comfortable turning an everyday bank visit into a sales opportunity. If you have a specific example of a time when you made this happen, be sure to share your story. You can also talk about any sales training you have received.", "\"Every customer service interaction should be considered an opportunity to upsell when the product or service will be of value to the customer. When I believe in the product or service, and it's going to benefit the customer, I am happy to upsell. I currently do so in my job, and consistently surpass the upselling, and cross-selling targets given to me.\"", "\"I have not received any formal sales training, but with a little bit of help, I believe that I would enjoy a sales component to my job. I am great at building customer relationships, and seeing a customers' need is part of delivering great service.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "How do our fees at Company ABC stack up against traditional banks?", "answers": ["Credit unions are non-profit where banks are for profit. For this reason, the fees at Company ABC will be lower and more reasonable than the large banks where people typically do business. With that said, credit unions sometimes have higher interest rates than traditional banks. \n\nThe interviewer would like to know that you have done some research on Company ABC and understand how their offering stacks up against traditional banks.", "\"Because Company ABC is member-owned, I see that you have the upper hand when it comes to  CD rates, loans, and mortgages, credit unions often have the upper hand with lower fees. Right now, the advantage appears to be around .05% on many Company ABC products.\"", "\"I understand that credit unions like Company ABC tend to have lower fees due to your non-profit and member-owned status. Credit unions do not have as many investors to please, which allows places like Company ABC to often offer lower fees on mortgages and loans.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "In this role, you will handle thousands of dollars of cash, payments, deposits, and funds transfers. This responsibility requires you to be detail-oriented, accurate, and honest. Does this describe you?", "answers": ["The best way to answer this question is to refer to your past performance. You might want to bring in a written performance review where your current boss mentions how reliable you are. You can offer up your references, or talk about a time your supervisor or co-workers complimented you on your work ethic.", "\"I have worked in the banking industry for twelve years without a discrepancy in my work. I believe this good work is due to my keen attention to detail, and the fact that I am honest enough to own up to an error I make in the workplace. When you call my references, they will attest to the fact that I am reliable and honest.\"", "\"When you call my references, they will most certainly tell you that I am honest and accurate in my work. In the banking industry, it's imperative that I am detail-oriented. I have not experienced an issue or discrepancy thus far, and I will continue to be careful and attentive in my work here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Do you have any formal education that will help you succeed in this role?", "answers": ["Your formal education might be on your resume, but it's time to dig a bit deeper than merely stating your degree. The interviewer wants you to take the time to walk them through which aspects of your education will be most helpful in this role with Company ABC. Think about any transferable skills you gained or any related subjects where you excelled. \n\nIf you do not have formal post-secondary education, you could refer to your high school education (only if you are a recent HS graduate). Otherwise, think of some online learning you have recently completed.", "\"I have a Bank Teller Certificate of Completion. My coursework included general banking classes, fraud prevention training, and exercises in daily transaction balancing. This coursework is valuable and helped me to gain a great start in my banking career.\"", "\"I am a recent high-school graduate and feel that, as a top student, I bring a few valuable transferable skills. These include etiquette, good written and oral communication skills, great memorization abilities, and a keen willingness to learn. I look forward to the formal training from Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Have you been trained in the proper techniques for detecting counterfeit cash and fraudulent checks?", "answers": ["Detecting counterfeit cash or fraudulent checks is an important skill to possess when working in the banking industry. Approximately $150 million worth of counterfeit money is currently circulating in the US. For this reason, it's crucial that banking professionals possess the knowledge necessary to detect fake bills. \n\nIt can be simple to detect counterfeit cash, especially with the technology and systems that banks have in place; however, checks can be a bit trickier. Talk about any training you have received. If you are self-taught or new to the industry, that's okay too! Assure the interviewer that you will be careful and detailed with each member transaction.", "\"I have received formal training in my current role and am very confident in my ability to detect counterfeit cash and fraudulent checks. There are many steps to take with cash, including looking forraised printing, blurry borders, lack of red and blue threads, watermark authenticity, and more. Checks can be a bit trickier, so I first look for a perforated edge, the check number, and the logo of the bank from where the check originated. Rest assured that I am meticulous and keen on detail.\"", "\"Fraudulent checks can be a challenge to detect. I know that one of the most important factors to look at is the MICR line, which is at the bottom of every authentic check. When running my finger over the ink on the MICR line, it should feel smooth. On many fake checks, this line will feel bumpy and raised. When it comes to counterfeit cash, I look at the quality of the paper, how the watermark reacts to the light, and its corresponding numbers. I have strong attention to detail and will be very careful with every transaction I complete at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Tell me about one career achievement you have set for yourself this year.", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know that you have ambitions related to growing your career in the banking industry. When you have goals on the horizon, you show the interviewer that you have an interest in advancing your career and staying in your industry for a long time to come. \n\nWhen you do not have goals set, the interviewer can interpret this as you being unmotivated and disengaged. Your goals can be as simple as finishing an online course, learning a new skill, or reaching a sales target.", "\"One achievement I would like to see this year is to make the top 3 for cross-selling at my current bank. My targets and goals are simple, but I like to exceed them, no matter what they are. The more successful my bank is, the better we can serve our customers.\"", "\"Next month, I am graduating with my business administration degree. My goal is to land an exceptional internship, like this one at Company ABC and get my career started on the right foot!\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Are you okay with routine work, or do you prefer a mix of responsibilities?", "answers": ["Much of a banking environment will be routine; however, the customers you interact with will change daily. So, although banking may offer routine, there is still variety in your day. Show the interviewer that you can handle the balance. \n\nLet the interviewer know that you understand you will have the same goals and processes each day. At the same time, show that you can manage the challenge that comes with customer interaction and other factors that deliver unpredictability in the workplace.", "\"I enjoy both working in a routine but also having a mix of responsibilities. In my current position, my schedule and goals are the same every day. What changes daily are my clients and their needs. These needs are where my day can become unpredictable. I enjoy that variety because it keeps me on my toes, engaged, and excited to come to work every day.\"", "\"Although it may seem routine, no day is the same for me in the banking industry. Generally speaking, my job function remains the same every day, but my customers offer me variety in my day. I am pleased with the pace that this role offers.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Do you consider yourself a logical person, able to make sound judgments under pressure?", "answers": ["A logical person will typically: \n\n- Pay close attention to detail, ensuring to avoid small errors\n- Be a careful communicator with carefully chosen words and questions\n- Lean on facts versus emotion or opinion\n\nTell a story of a time when you delivered a sound judgment under pressure by using your logical skills. If possible, keep your answer work-related. \n\nIf you are new to your career, you can use an example from your post-secondary experience or volunteer work. Be sure to showcase your logic and reasoning abilities. Share a brief overview of the problem, discuss the pro/cons of each decision you could have made, and tell the interviewer why the solution you chose was the best.", "\"I use good logic every day! As a bank teller, I face a multitude of issues surrounding people needing access to their funds. I use logic by figuring out how to arrange a customers' financial needs to meet policy while taking the path of least resistance. Just recently, I had a customer with an issue due to a hold on their paycheck when their rent was due. I was able to move the funds to another bank account that did not have a hold policy. This action enabled me to release the funds and help the customer pay their rent on time.\"", "\"Yes, I do consider myself very logical, which always helps me to make sound judgments. Just yesterday, I had a customer who was upset because our new bank teller in training was taking too long to complete her transaction. I am the assistant manager, so I stepped in to alleviate the situation. By showing the customer that I could expedite the process, she was able to calm down and be kinder to the trainee. It was not ideal for me to spend my time on a simple customer issue like this; however, it was important that I brought a level head to the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Have you ever been terminated? If so, what were the circumstances surrounding your termination?", "answers": ["Company ABC has to be very careful who they hire, since their employees are privy to sensitive customer and financial information. If you have faced job termination, you must be upfront about the situation. There is a high likelihood that Company ABC will call references, and perform background checks including employment verification so its best that you be open and truthful from the start. \n\nBeing let go from your position is an unfortunate event; however, it happens to the best of us and often for situations that are out of our control. It's best to own up to it if you have ever lost your job. Be brief in your explanation but also let the interviewer know what you learned.", "\"Luckily, I have never experienced a termination; however, I understand that it happens to the best people at times. If I were up for termination, based on job performance, I would appreciate an open and transparent conversation with my boss. This way, I would have the opportunity to adjust my approach and redeem myself.\"", "\"I experienced a termination earlier in my career; I was not as prompt as I am today and bit off more than I could chew between being a full-time student and a part-time retail employee. After coming to work late a couple of times, my boss lets me go. It was embarrassing and changed the course for me. I am much more dedicated and have not been late for work in years.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Your background is not in banking. Tell me what skills and characteristics qualify you for this position with Company ABC.", "answers": ["Many people leave their primary industry and move into roles within banking. If you are transitioning between sectors, expect to answer a question like this and come prepared to defend why you want to change industries. \n\nYour answer should be more profound than the typical, 'banking seems interesting to me' type of response. Think about why you feel that this transition into banking will be beneficial for your long term career. \n\nNext, the interviewer would like to know which transferable skills you bring to this position. There are many ways that you can be a fit for a job, even though you do not come with direct industry experience. Think about the variety of skills that you have and how those can benefit Company ABC.", "\"Time management, analytical thinking, and attention to detail are just some of the transferable skills I bring from the retail industry into banking. I have begun to study terminology for the banking industry and will have a firm grasp before my start date. I am fully prepared to transition into banking, an industry where I can grow and learn for many years to come.\"", "\"I come from a retail sales setting; however, there are many similarities between my current role at your needs at Company ABC. For starters, I am accustomed to sales targets and goals, delivering excellent client service, and cross-selling. Other useful skills include analytical thinking and strong research capabilities from my university experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Are you a patient person? How do you boost your patience level in challenging situations?", "answers": ["Have you ever stood in line at the bank and lost patience because of how long the line was taking? Now, put yourself in the shoes of a bank teller who has to face many challenges every day. In the banking industry, you may need to deal with customers who move slowly, customers who argue against bank policy, or those who are flustered due to a long line. \n\nPatience is a virtue, which means that it isn't always easy to come by! Show the interviewer that you are patient individual by giving an example of a time when you displayed a lot of patience in a frustrating situation. Alternately, you can rely on a performance review where your boss commended you on your high tolerance to stress. \n\nImpatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in coworkers and clients, so it is essential that you showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations.", "\"I do consider myself to be a patient person; however, it's more of a learned skill that I have mastered over the years. I never demonstrate my frustration or impatience with others in the workplace. To do so is rude and counterproductive. To boost my patience level in challenging situations, I remind myself to have empathy for the other person and what they may be going through that day.\"", "\"Yes, I am a patient person. I like to learn, teach others, and take careful steps, ensuring that my work is well done. To boost my patience level in a challenging situation, I remind myself that I will come out of the circumstance with more knowledge than when I came into the situation. I take the approach of a student.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Do you have plans for continued education?", "answers": ["In many instances, you are not required to hold a post-secondary degree to work in a bank teller role. Other positions within banking do require a further degree. For the sake of career growth, the interviewer would like to know if you are planning to obtain higher education. Of course, this question applies only to those who have completed just a high-school diploma. If you are planning to return to school, discuss what you would want to take. Your answer should reflect an interest in continuing your career with Company ABC. \n\nCompany ABC may even offer tuition support or a reimbursement program for employees who wish to continue their education. If they do provide this type of perk, you can indeed show interest but make sure that your continued education aspirations are related to the industry and job. For instance, you may want to stick to a finance-related topic rather than saying you would like to take courses in zoology.", "\"Continued education is important to remain knowledgeable and relevant in the banking industry. I would be interested in earning a Bachelor's Degree in Finance at some point; allowing me to grow with Company ABC into a lender-based role.\"", "\"In banking, it is important to stay on top of your industry. For that reason, I believe that related coursework is always beneficial. I have had my eye on obtaining my MBA one day. Of course, I would obtain this throughout a couple of years as I work full time. Does Company ABC encourage continued education, or offer tuition reimbursement?\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "One small error can throw off our entire balance. How do you react when you do something wrong at work?", "answers": ["In the banking industry, even a small mistake can make a massive impact on business operations. How you react to an error made will tell the interviewer a great deal about you and your honesty level. \n\nPerhaps the mistake is one that could land you in a lot of trouble. The hiring authority at Company ABC wants to know if you would try to hide the incident, or if you would tell your manager before the situation went beyond repair. Of course, the best way to answer this question is to show accountability.", "\"I can be my toughest critic when it comes to making mistakes. If I made an error, I would tell my manager right away. If a manager were not available, I would bring the situation to the attention of a co-worker capable of helping me fix the issue. Even being pennies off in a day can make a big impact so you can rest assured that I will deliver perfection.\"", "\"I am an honest person who is accountable and eager to learn. These traits ensure that I ill take every action necessary to do my job perfectly. If I make a mistake, I want to learn from that error so I would most certainly bring the error to the attention of my manager. The sooner, the better, so that there are as few consequences as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "What do you enjoy about your career in banking?", "answers": ["Job satisfaction is a vital factor for success, for both you as an employee and Company ABC. Employee turnover is an essential conversation in the workplace as it cost employers thousands of dollars to replace well-trained employees each time one moves on to another job. \n\nWhen a company understands what brings satisfaction to their team members, they are better equipped to motivate their team members and ensure a long and healthy relationship. Talk to the interviewer about what satisfies you about your career, and why you work in banking.", "\"I have worked very hard to gain a leadership position within the banking industry. Being a teller manager allows me to be on the front lines training others to have lucrative careers, while still allowing me to be client-facing. I genuinely believe that my work matters, and that is what I enjoy most about a career in banking.\"", "\"Working in banking, I gain the most satisfaction from knowing my clients are gaining a solid financial future. I care about the success of my customers, and when they are well-equipped to pay off debt, save money, and even retire early; it makes me so happy!\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Looking back to your most recent performance review; what was one area for improvement, and one positive?", "answers": ["This question is another way to ask about your strengths and weaknesses. By asking for specific performance evaluations, the hiring authority is more likely to get a direct answer and a better idea of the full picture. \n\nIf you do not have formal performance evaluations, you can also lean on a recent conversation with your direct manager. Your positive highlight can be big or small, but be sure to relate your positive points to the requirements of the Company ABC job posting. \n\nWhen you talk about your area for improvement, avoid mentioning something that would make you ineligible for the position. For instance, if you are interviewing for a banking position, simple math should not be your weakness. Also, be sure to discuss that you are actively working to improve this weakness.", "\"My most recent performance review was very positive. My boss is thrilled with my ability to analyze data on a client account very quickly; allowing me to see cross-selling opportunities quickly. One area for improvement was to speed up my work a little bit and get through my line of customers a bit faster. I am cautious at work; however, I am training myself to perform certain tasks faster without cutting any corners.\"", "\"Formal performance evaluations are not part of my regular role, but I do get a lot of feedback daily.  My manager comments quite often on my product knowledge, and how well I retain information, even with brand new roll-outs. One thing that I can work on is my typing speed. I am accurate and type about 50wpm, which isn't too bad, but I am practicing to get to 75wpm.\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "Do you have any questions about Company ABC or this job?", "answers": ["When you come to a job interview prepared with intelligent questions, you are showing the interviewer that you have put care, thought, and attention into preparing yourself for the interview. Make sure the quality of your questions is high. Your questions should be insightful, and not subjects like 'How many locations do you have?' when you know that this information is available through a simple online search. \n\nSome great questions to ask include: \n\n- What do you believe sets Company ABC apart from other local Credit Unions? \n- What compliment does Company ABC receive most often from its members? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the Company ABC  goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"I appreciate the opportunity to ask a few questions! What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\"", "\"I do have a couple of questions prepared; thank you for asking. What is the biggest challenge facing credit unions in the next year? Could you share with me your employee turnover rate, and what your training program looks like?\""]}, {"topic": "Credit+Unions", "question": "How much do you earn in your current role?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know if their salary offering will be enough to win you over. Often, potential employers base your offer on what you are currently earning. So, although this question may feel very direct, the better you answer it, the higher the chance that your job offer will be satisfactory. \n\nIf you can, be transparent about your most recent earnings and your future expectations. Keep your answer simple, and to the point. It is okay to ask the interviewer what they are offering in return!", "\"My current annual salary is $48,000 per year. I seek a compensation plan aligned with the more significant responsibilities in this role. Could you share with me the compensation plan here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am a recent business graduate, seeking compensation that is fair considering my recent education. Being new to my career, I am most interested in joining an organization that will help me to grow my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include skills that will potentially benefit this potential new employer.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "\"There are many skills I gained in my most recent position as I had a great training program and my boss was a strong mentor. If I had to choose three top skills I would say that the biggest ones were effective multitasking, solid closing skills, and cold calling abilities.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How can Company ABC motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each of their employees is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"I am a natural salesperson, so the best way to motivate me is through performance incentives. In my current position, I have been in the president's club for the past three consecutive years. I am highly motivated by the vacation that I am awarded annually.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Tell me about a time where you had to analyze information in order to make a recommendation.", "answers": ["Talk about your attention to detail and sharp focus on data and statistics. If the job requires you to take an analytical approach to solving problems, think back on your experience to offer up an example. Give as much insight into your process to show you are capable of taking an analytical approach to problem-solving.", "\"I worked for a financial firm last year and had a client who was looking for investment recommendations. I gathered data on the stocks they were interested in, sorting through trends and historical data to determine the most promising returns.\"", "\"As a financial service professional, I am always analyzing information before creating a path of recommendation for my clients. I am highly skilled when it comes to data analysis. My abilities stem from my statistics and analysis related courses while obtaining my Bachelor's degree in finance.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we offer many different financial services. Which aspect of financial services are you best versed in?", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your expertise that best relates to the business they specialize in. This is where it's important to have searched Company ABC prior to your interview! Be sure to finish by asking the interviewer the services they prefer you be versed in. This way you can overcome any potential objections later.", "\"After researching your website I see that you specialize in Investment and Hedge Fund management. My specialty is definitely Investment management. Is there a certain specialty you are looking for in your next hire?\"", "\"I have a wide range of expertise when it comes to financial services. I see that Company ABC is looking for a candidate who brings experience in X, Y, and Z. I have expert level knowledge in all of these areas.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How do you believe your coworkers would describe you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you are seen by your colleagues.  Select approximately three words that truly define who you are. Be sure to choose words that radiate positive thoughts!", "\"I believe that my coworkers, if asked, would describe me as a reliable person who is always ready to submit the best work possible. My work ethic has never been questioned, and I am very proud with the work that I have submitted in my career, so far.\"", "Here are some other great keywords you could use: \n\n- Encouraging\n- Caring\n- Knowledgeable\n- Reliable  \n- Focused \n- Honest\n- Assertive\n- Tenacious\n- Motivated\n- Ambitions\n- Conscientious"]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Would you consider expanding your education to include an MBA? Why or why not?", "answers": ["Depending on the role you are interviewing for, you may have completed a Bachelors degree in a finance or business related field. Talk to the interviewer about your potential plans for continued education. It's always best to leave the door open for opportunity!", "\"Although I have my Bachelor's degree in Finance as well as my CFA and FRM designations, I would absolutely consider returning to complete an MBA. Do you encourage continued education for your employees at Company ABC?\"", "\"An MBA is never a bad idea; however, that would be a long term goal for me. At the moment, I am focusing on building my financial services portfolio and gaining additional knowledge through industry related workshops and courses.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Every employee with Company ABC is expected to be sales-minded and target driven. Walk me through your experience in sales based roles.", "answers": ["Briefly take the interviewer through your sales based work history. Be sure to highlight your best results. This is where it is very important to know your sales numbers before walking into your interview.", "\"I have been in a sales based role for the past 10 years. With Company A, my best year I finished 125% to quota. With Company B, I began from the ground up and left with a portfolio of business worth $$$. In my last position, with Company C, I was the top grossing financial services employee in our branch at 167% to target.\"", "\"At this point in my career I do not have a lot of financial sales related experience; however, I am well versed in a variety of business development and cold calling techniques. I fully understand how to build a sales pipeline and see the importance of building a referrals based business.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "As a professional in the financial services industry, you must have great integrity. Do you consider yourself an honest and trustworthy person?", "answers": ["Due to the sensitive nature of your work, honesty is a core requirement in everything that you do. Assure the interviewer that you are an honest and trustworthy person, worthy of employment with Company ABC.", "\"I have often been told that I am one of the most trustworthy people out there. In addition to being raised to always make the right choice, I have no fear when it comes do delivering honesty. You are more than welcome to check in with my references as well. They will speak highly of my character.\"", "\"Integrity is very important in the financial services industry. Yes, I absolutely consider myself to be honest and trustworthy.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "When it comes to financial services, which focus do you find the most rewarding?", "answers": ["There are so many areas of focus when it comes to financial services. Talk to the interviewer about the areas of finance that you enjoy working on the most. Be sure to acknowledge some areas of focus within Company ABC when you answer this question.", "\"I find many areas of financial services to be intriguing. After researching your company further, I see that you focus on Capital Market Services and Brokerage Services. I really enjoy working in both areas but primarily Capital Market Services  and restructuring debt.\"", "\"One of the primary reasons behind my application to your company was that you offer Commercial Services. This is an area or strength for me that I look forward to evolving even further.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of value in the continued training of our employees. If you could expand your knowledge in any financial service area, which would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you would be willing to commit more time to expanding your financial services knowledge. If you were given the opportunity to expand your industry related training, which area would you choose?", "\"I really appreciate that Company ABC puts so much emphasis on the education of your employees. If I could choose to further my education in any area of financial services, I would choose to learn more about hedge funds.\"", "\"I take professional development very seriously and have attended a variety of courses this year including Financial Markets and Products, and Personal Financial Planning II. If I could take another, I would definitely choose to learn more about Personal Financial Planning but taking the Level III course.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Talk to me about your post-secondary education and how you feel it will help you in a career with Company ABC.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your post-secondary education. Which aspects of your education do you look forward to applying to your future career with Company ABC?", "\"I have a Bachelor's Degree in Accounting with a focus on Financial Law. I feel that the Financial Law aspect will help me immensely in my career with Company ABC because it is a strong major that helped me to understand the effects of all actions in business. It's caused me to strengthen my analytical mind and problem solving capabilities.\"", "\"My education has been primarily on-the-job training and additional coursework on mutual funds, and RESP's. You will see a full list of my certificates on my resume. In addition to these credentials, I have enrolled in a Financial Planners workshop this fall.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How do you stay on top of new trends in the financial services industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that your passion for financial services goes beyond your work hours. Do you keep on top of industry news and trends on your off time? Assure the interviewer that you are well immersed in the industry.", "\"I stay on top of financial service trends through a variety of blogs, news sites and financial magazines. My favorite finance news site at the moment is businessinsider.com.\"", "\"I believe that it is crucial for me to stay on top of news in the financial services industry if I hope to be a success. I have joined multiple meet up groups to network with industry peers. It has really helped my network and given me insight into how other financial service professionals are making their careers flourish.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Due to the sensitivity of our business, in order to work for Company ABC, you must be able to pass a criminal background check. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["If you do not have any criminal history, this is an answer that will be very simple and concise. If you do have a criminal history, now is the time to disclose it.", "\"I do not have a criminal history of any kind and I am happy to comply with any form of background check you require.\"", "\"I should disclose to you that I have a mark on my criminal record. I have a DUI from 1998. Since then I have maintained a clean record and I am willing to comply with any form of background check that you require.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we put great pride in our customer service. How do you ensure that your clients are well taken care of?", "answers": ["In which ways do you ensure that your clients are well taken care of? Talk to the interviewer about your customer service skills.", "\"In my current position I take many steps to ensuring great customer service. To me, this means having excellent follow up and strong active listening skills. I remember the names of my client's children and I call to congratulate them on milestones. I will keep in touch to update them on new services as well.\"", "\"I can assure you that, if hired, I would put the customers of Company ABC first. When working in the financial services world, your customers can determine your success. I have a very high referrals rate which tells me that my customers are happy.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Tell me about the largest financial portfolio you have been responsible for.", "answers": ["Chances are you have gained a lot of momentum through your financial services career; likely being responsible for a larger portfolio every year. Assure the interviewer that you can handle the level of responsibility they are expecting to hand over to you.", "\"My responsibilities have always increased over time and in my last position I was responsible for a portfolio of $$$. Can you share with me the size of portfolio that I would be working with here at Company ABC?\"", "\"I am newer to my financial services career and have worked very hard to develop a strong portfolio this past year. Currently my portfolio is worth $$. What size of portfolio would I be responsible for at Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Do you have experience in cold calling? If so, tell me about your targets and results.", "answers": ["Cold calling, warm calling, prospecting, and building a sales pipeline - these are all tasks generally associated with most financial services roles. Assure the interviewer that you are capable and willing to do what it takes to get the sales results you need!", "\"I have experience in cold calling and all other forms of generating new and repeat business. I took a workshop last year on the art of cold calling as well. In my most recent position I made approximately 100 cold calls per week.\"", "\"I am new to my career in financial services and sales; however, I have taken an online course focused on cold calling. This course was incredibly helpful and I look forward to meeting and exceeding my targets with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Aside from your post-secondary degree, what other financial services related training and certifications do you possess?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know about any financial related designations you may currently have. If you do not have any special designations, are you planning to complete any?", "\"My goal is to gain at least one additional certificate per year. I have achieved XX so far and next year, a course on XX is on my bucket list!\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "What qualities do you feel a successful manager should have?", "answers": ["Some great qualities of a manager are:\n\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\n- Strong relationship building skills\n- Taking ownership for the team's errors and mistakes\n- Excelling at motivating others\n- Providing kudos/recognition to your team\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\n- Having a vision for the future\n\nThese are just a few to get started!", "\"I feel that a successful manager should be patient, strive to be a mentor, and be willing to receive constructive feedback from their team. As a manager, I want to have a team that trusts me and comes to me for professional development and coaching.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How long will it take you to make a meaningful contribution to our team at Company ABC?", "answers": ["If you were to be the successful candidate with Company ABC, when do you expect to make a viable contribution to the organization? Talk to the interviewer about your plan to make a fast impact.", "\"I am interested in making an impact on your organization right away and have already crafted a plan to make that happen. I am a very strong business development professional and I plan to take the territory and expand it to include additional rural areas. This should amount to a strong increase in revenue within the first 9 months of my on boarding.\"", "\"My plan, if hired by Company ABC, is to make an impact as soon as possible. I have researched this position and am very eager so I have created a 90 day impact plan that I would like to share with you.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How would you rate your performance in this interview so far?", "answers": ["This question is meant to create a little bit of stress. If you are not confident and prepared, a question like this will make it very obvious to the interviewer. Give a very honest response! \n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is going well: \"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "\"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "If you feel that your performance in the interview is not going well: \"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more that I can clarify for you I would be happy to do so.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Describe to me a time when you made an error in your current or former position, and the impact your mistake made? How did you correct the error, what did you learn from it?", "answers": ["Everyone makes mistakes, and no one is perfect. The interviewer knows that too and is asking this question to see how you handle situations when you make mistakes. Give an example that demonstrates how you took responsibility for your error and fixed it. Also, what you learned from the experience as a result. Sometimes learning from our mistakes allows us to gain some valuable tools.", "\"When I worked as a financial services rep, I accidentally double booked two clients for an appointment in one of the time slots. I realized the mistake after I was double checking my calendar and called the clients right away and apologized for my mistake. As a result of this experience, I always made sure to check the time slots on my calendar twice.\"", "\"When starting my current position, I had some struggles with learning Salesforce and let the frustrations get the best of me. I felt like a failure and was ready to give up. Once my boss pulled me aside and reminded me that everyone struggles with brand new technology, I was able to relax. I ended up taking an online course on the program so that I could fast-track my learning and avoid further frustration. What I learned was that only I am responsible for my learning and there are always ways to overcome challenges, if you look for the answers and are prepared to work for them.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["Many people find that performance incentives can be very motivating and yet others find them to cause anxiety. Talk to the interviewer about your feelings regarding performance incentives and how they may or may not affect your work performance.", "\"I feel that performance incentives are a great idea. They keep an employee motivated to do a great job and ensure that they are on top of their KPI's. The majority of people are very enthused about being rewarded for their successes.\"", "\"I am prepared to give my best, whether a performance incentive is offered or not. Incentives can be a great idea, but I feel they should not be too simple to achieve. Most sales professionals respond well to a good challenge.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "If you could alter your career path, in any way, what would you change?", "answers": ["This question will help the interviewer to understand if you have a long and continued passion for your career. Talk to the interviewer about an alternate career path that you might choose but be sure to keep it related to the position for which you are interviewing.", "\"If I could change anything about my career path, I would have stayed in post-secondary studies for longer to upgrade in my field. I feel that this would have given me the advancement I seek now, many years earlier.\"", "\"I believe in looking forward, and not back. Every decision that I have made has brought me here so I would not change a thing.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Company ABC seeks out natural and confident leaders. What leadership qualities do you possess?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you can take on a leadership role even if it is not a formal leadership title that you possess. Everyone has leadership capabilities, whether they come in the form of training a new employee or merely leading by example.", "\"I feel that I am good at motivating a team. Last year, I motivated my sales team every day, through small incentives and awards, and we ended up being the top sales team in the company for the year!\"", "Some great qualities of a leader are:\n\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\n- Strong relationship building skills\n- Taking ownership for the team's errors and mistakes\n- Excelling at motivating others\n- Providing kudos to your team\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\n- Having a vision for the future\n\nThese are just a few to get you started!  With which qualities do you most identify?"]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Companies will have confidentiality agreements for a variety of reasons. These could be to protect their trade secrets or to ensure that you do not bring clients over on the occasion that you leave their company. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements.", "\"I have never, to my knowledge, broken a confidentiality agreement. Despite my reasons for leaving a position, I would never choose to hurt a previous employer in any way.\"", "\"No, I have never broken a confidentiality agreement. I respect my employers, current and past, and highly value being a person of integrity.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Honesty is of utmost importance to us at Company ABC. Have you ever taken the fall for a situation, where it was really not your fault, in order to protect a coworker?", "answers": ["Taking the fall for a situation, in order to protect a coworker, is a tricky situation. It can show teamwork but it may not be the most honest thing to do. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on taking the fall for something you did not do.", "\"I do not believe in 'taking the fall' for people based on protecting them. Transparency is always a good idea and if something went wrong then it needs to be addressed in order to prevent it from happening again. When it comes to clients, I will apologize on behalf of the company for errors. In that case, I will do what it takes to protect the company's reputation.\"", "\"I will always help a well-meaning co-worker to save face when necessary. With that said, I will not lie in order to save a coworker from the consequences of their mistakes.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Accuracy is important to us at Company ABC. Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking and proofreading are essential parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean, work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is imperative to submit error-free work.\"", "\"I do my best to put great work out, at all times. I believe in double checking my work although I must admit that I have fallen victim to the odd mistake like the best of us!\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "Company ABC is looking for employees who are dedicated to their clients. How often do you take work home with you?", "answers": ["The majority of people will work overtime hours or take work home with them on occasion. Talk to the interviewer about how frequently you take your work home.", "\"I make sure to utilize my work hours very efficiently so the only time that I take my work home is when there is an extremely stringent deadline. I would say that, overall, I take my work home maybe twice per month. It's all about being diligent with your time in the office!\"", "\"I take my work home with me anytime I feel that it will give me an edge over my competition, or benefit my clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "When have you shown a willingness to learn a new method or new approach to solving a problem?", "answers": ["It is a great skill to have when you can approach a problem in a new way. Discuss with the interviewer your ability to approach a problem using modern methods.", "\"When our company came under new management last year many new methods and policies came into place. I was able to learn many new approaches to our challenges in sales and customer management. I quite enjoyed the process.\"", "\"In my current position, I am faced with learning new sales methods and client approaches on a regular basis. I am always the first to embrace these new sales pitches because I truly believe the bigger diversity we can offer our clients, the better.\""]}, {"topic": "Financial+Services", "question": "There will be great days at Company ABC and some days that are tougher to get through. When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"Setbacks are tough, but I truly believe that everything happens for a reason. I am a creative person and will always find a way to recover from a setback.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Tell me about your biggest failure and how you recovered.", "answers": ["Everyone has failed at some point in their career. The important part is how we pick ourselves up and bounce back after the perceived failure. Many failures can be traced back to negative thinking, insecurities, lack of research, unproductive behavior, restricted thinking, poor communication skills, and lack of passion or goals. Give the interviewer an example of a time when the outcome was not what you wanted or expected, but you were able to recover. Discuss what you learned from the situation.", "\"One of the bigger perceived failures was right at the beginning of my post-secondary career when I did not graduate when I was expected to. I encountered a few personal factors that pushed my graduation date back one year. It was embarrassing at the time, but truth be told, I am thankful that I could complete my degree at a comfortable pace. I finished on the Dean's List and am very proud of that accomplishment.\"", "\"For the first three years of my career, I was terrible at graciously receiving feedback. Had I been able to receive feedback without becoming defensive, I believe that I could have grown in my career much faster. Last year, I took a workshop on giving and receiving feedback, which helped a great deal. Now, I understand how to have these types of conversations and how to implement the constructive criticism that I receive.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Company ABC wants to ensure that you are a strategic fit. Tell me more about your investing strategy.", "answers": ["There are a variety of investment strategies, and when you and your client are on the same page, that is when you can see a lot of success. Some investment styles include: \n\n- Value Investing\n- Income Investing \n- Growth Investing \n- Small-Cap Investing \n- Socially Responsible Investing\n\nThere is a chance that you have utilized all types of investment strategies! With that said, the interviewer would like to know if there is one in particular that you lean to the most often. Your answer should align well with the core strategies and values of Company ABC.", "\"I am a big Warren Buffet fan and, learned a great deal from him on the principles behind Value Investing. This investing style focuses on buying undervalued stocks. This approach takes a great deal of research; however, research is one of my strongest suits as a portfolio manager. It often is a waiting game when it comes to the rising prices, so Value Investing also requires a lot of patience, which I refer to as 'buy and hold.' This investment style is not for everyone, but the payoffs can be excellent if the investor is patient.\"", "\"Peter Lynch is someone in the investment industry that I admire. He introduced me to the art of Growth Investing; a strategy focused on capital appreciation. First, I seek out companies that show above-average growth through revenues and profits. Even if the share price doesn't seem low, or like 'a deal,' I believe that it's worth a look. I understand that Growth Investing is riskier, and not for everyone; however, it can pay off well when we look at companies within emerging markets.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "How does your post-secondary education relate to a career in wealth management?", "answers": ["Nearly every high-end wealth management firm will require you to have a post-secondary degree related to finance. If your degree is not related to finance, be prepared to defend your educational background. Your formal education and industry training might be on your resume; however, the interviewer would like you to dig deeper and bring this education to life for them. Discuss how your education has prepared you for this job with Company ABC.", "\"I earned my masters' degree in finance from ABC University. My degree exposed me to the financial world and specific topics such as bonds, econometrics, economics, corporate finance, governmental finance, individual investment, statistics, and portfolio management. I am grateful for my education and how well it has supported me in my career.\"", "\"I will never be finished when it comes to my education and learning. Although my degree is in business administration, and not specifically finance, my school did prepare me very well for a career in wealth management. I took courses in economics, finance, management, and marketing; all important facets of wealth management.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Company ABC provides fundamental insights and analysis for clients in the equity, fixed income, currency, and commodities markets. Which areas of research are most important to you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know which areas of research you find to be the most important and applicable to your role in wealth management. The truth is, all of these topics are important, yet you may lean towards understanding one a bit better over others. Discuss what you believe to be an essential area of research without overlooking the others at the same time.", "\"I have read many articles by Company ABC on all of these topics. I would say they are equally important; however, I find research on commodities markets to be the most intriguing. I like to learn about the hard commodities we offer in our region and how to leverage them to benefit my clients.\"", "\"Currency is fundamental to research and understand, especially as my portfolio of clients is global. With that said, I also believe its essential that I am well rounded by spending my time reading articles and gaining insight on other topics such as equity, fixed income, commodities, and more.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Tell me about a stock you follow. Why should I buy them?", "answers": ["There is no real right or wrong answer to this question, as it's hypothetical. The interviewer would like to know more about the type of stocks that you follow but more importantly, how you would present them to a client. Think of a stock that you are diligently following and make a compelling argument as to why the interviewer should invest!", "\"I am always in tune with the 'best of' and 'must-watch' stock lists. Most recently, Canopy Growth, the worlds' largest cannabis producer, has caught my eye. As cannabis becomes legalized in many areas of the world and is used medically more and more, the company is expanding to Germany, Spain, Denmark, and Australia. What ups the ante is that Canopy Growth is in partnership with an alcoholic beverage company. This partnership gives them a significant advantage when cannabis-based beer and other alcoholic beverages become mainstream.\"", "\"I tend to keep a considerable amount of interest in medical and pharma and so, for that reason, I believe looking into Gilead would be very lucrative. The drugmaker helped turn HIV from a fatal disease into a manageable chronic ailment and developed a cure for Hepatitic C. They have become a $100B company along the way, and there is a lot of buzz surrounding a change in leadership which is sure to produce even bigger results in the years to come.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What differentiates Company ABC from other high-end wealth management firms?", "answers": ["There are many significant high-end wealth management firms out there, but Company ABC wants to know why they are the stand-out firm for you. Why do you want to work for them versus their competitors? \n\nTake the time to carve out a unique answer that goes far beyond the surface. A surface answer would be because you know someone who works there, for instance. A great response would be dropping a specific reason as to why the company is unique.", "\"In addition to your sparkling reputation in this industry, I appreciate the immense efforts Company ABC is taking to close the gender gap in the finance industry. Your programs have trained thousands of women entrepreneurs in developing economies around the world. Company ABC knows that empowering women makes sound economic sense. This awareness is one reason why I want to work for you and just one way that you stand far above your competitors.\"", "Company ABC is huge on philanthropy, and giving is a significant part of my moral makeup. I understand that your firm has donated nearly $1B in the last 20 years to charitable efforts, and in the form of student grants. Your efforts to help underserved children, as well as refugee initiatives, are remarkable and stand out from the rest.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "The wealth management industry is highly competitive. When it comes to your performance, would you say you 'love to win,' or you 'hate to lose?'", "answers": ["Wealth management, depending on your job function, can be a cutthroat industry. If you are a wealth manager or private banker, often you only 'eat what you kill' meaning you are paid only when you close business. \n\nOften, wealth manager seats are revolving as it's easy to get fired from clients when they feel you are underperforming. These are just some of the ways that you need to remain competitive in the wealth management industry. There isn't a wrong answer to this question. The interviewer would like to see that you are not a sore loser and that you bring the competition needed to succeed at Company ABC. Speak a bit about your competitive side and your desire to succeed.", "\"I love to win although losing is inevitable now and then. When I am not winning, it's essential that I learn from the experience, and implement changes from it, rather than dwell. As a highly commissioned wealth management professional, the love to win on behalf of my clients is what drives me.\"", "\"'I hate to lose' is more descriptive of me, although not in a negative way. I am a bit of a perfectionist when it comes to the work that I deliver, which means that I dislike disappointing my boss, my clients, and myself. With that said, I know there is always something to learn from losing.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Company ABC wealth managers work independently.  What makes you an entrepreneurial minded professional?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants assurance that you will be able to run your client portfolio as though it is your own business. You will be responsible for building your client list, maintaining relationships, and adjusting your business to the ever-changing economic environments and trends that we face today. Share with the interviewer what an entrepreneurial mindset means to you, and how you go about exercising that mentality in your day to day work.", "\"An entrepreneurial mindset, to me, means to continually seek out new challenges and think about my career vision every day. Also, I am an exceptional problem solver. I think quickly and can get myself out of most situations by looking at the issue from various angles. I willingly accept feedback and criticism, then take that feedback to find new ways of working. These are just some of the entrepreneurial qualities I will bring to Company ABC and my clients.\"", "\"For me, it's important that I continue to manage my portfolio of clients as though it's my own business. To do this, I pay for and attend industry conferences regularly. Rather than running straight to management, I reverse engineer problems and conduct research when an issue arises. Also, I take the opportunity to read as much as I can. I absorb myself wholly in topics related to finance, investments, and wealth management.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Think about a demanding boss, client, or co-worker. How did you learn to interact with this individual?", "answers": ["The wealth management industry is high-stakes and requires a great deal of thick skin at times. The interviewer wants to know how you interact with those who have challenging personalities. \n\nThink about an individual in the workplace who you found difficult to please, and how you ended up interacting with them successfully. Show the interviewer that you can adapt to a variety of personalities while remaining professional. Avoid speaking poorly of anyone and be sure to end your response on a positive note.", "\"I struggled most with an executive at my previous company. She was brought on with minimal experience in the finance industry but was known to be a 'turn-around artist' across multiple industries. She came out of the gates hard and lacked some professional couth. To win her over; I invited her to lunch with one of my biggest clients. I wanted her to see my work first-hand while also spending one-on-one time together. During that lunch, we bonded as humans, mothers, and professionals who had common goals. She learned a lot about the company and industry, and I learned a lot about the skills she brought from her previous roles.\"", "\"I have worked most of my career in the finance and banking industry, which attracts a large variety of personalities. I am a warm person by nature and have found it challenging to connect with those who are mostly analytical. My former boss was this way, so I adapted by sticking solely to the facts when in meetings; presenting data and minimal opinion. It wasn't the deepest relationship that I've had in my career, but I made it work.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "If you advised a client to hedge against risk in their portfolio, but they wanted to take an alternate action that could hurt their long-term goals, what would you do?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you take things such as a difference of opinion as an opportunity to dive back into your clients' needs. If you disagree on approach, this could be a sign that you need to revisit long-term goals with your client. Discuss how you carefully go over the pros and cons of these competing approaches. \n\nShow Company ABC that you are not afraid to be bold when necessary. This boldness may include telling your client that their approach is not a good idea. Maybe you bring in a second opinion, which will show the interviewer that you are not ego-driven; doing what is best for your client.", "\"A difference in opinion may cost me a client; however, I would rather lose a client than be a 'yes person' as the financial ship sinks. If a client wants to take a risk that I know will end up hurting them, I will flat out tell them that it's a bad idea. I will present a case using pros and cons, and if needed, will bring in a specialist on the issue to help the client see the bigger picture.\"", "\"If a client wanted to take a bad risk against their portfolio, I would present as much compelling data as possible, to convince them otherwise. If the situation were extreme, I am aware that I could lose the client. It's more important to me; however, that I help my client refrain from action that could hinder them, no matter how much we disagree.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you consider yourself analytically minded, or more creatively driven?", "answers": ["It's important to remember when answering this question that everyone can be analytically minded and creative at the same time. In fact, the two approaches can intertwine very well. \n\nSince being analytical is a significant part of working in the wealth management industry, keep your response more focused on your analytical capabilities. \n\nYour analytical mind may show up when it comes time to investigate a problem and research its solutions. Perhaps you are very methodical in how you approach your investment strategies. Talk a bit about your analytical mind, and how it will benefit Company ABC, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"My analytical skills shine through when detecting patterns in finance trends, observing and interpreting data, and theorizing on where the market is going. I incorporate my creative side when brainstorming ideas for my clients. I remain highly analytical since those important decisions lean on multiple market factors. I take pride in my ability to pivot between analytical and creative thinking.\"", "\"I work on strengthening my analytical skills every day. While attending university, I would collect and analyze information, problem-solve, and make decisions based on various sets of data. I will bring my analytical strengths to Company ABC to help you solve problems but at the same time, I will also bring a creative drive, ensuring that I put a human touch into business development and client relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Talk to me about one piece of financial news you are currently following.", "answers": ["This question allows the interviewer to get to know you a bit better; helping them to understand the issues that draw you in. Many topics in financial news could pique your interest. Discuss one piece of economic news that has caught your attention as of late. You can give your opinion on the topic; however, it's essential that you avoid going on a tangent regarding politics and other hot button topics.", "\"One topic I have been immersed in, primarily because so many of my clients have an interest, is China's GDP growth. China's growth has seen a 6.2% slump in Q2 of this year and the lowest percent in about 27 years. This topic is significant to me since China is the world's second-largest economy. We are starting to see the impact of the trade war between China and the US.\"", "\"I have been reading more in the news about water scarcity as a global phenomenon and how this could soon make water a good investment. Shortages in upcoming years could make water a precious commodity, making it a potential opportunity for investors. From the research I have conducted, I see that a small amount of traditional mutual funds and exchange-traded funds already invest in water. These investments are mainly around its delivery, testing, and cleaning. I believe there could be phenomenal growth as governments strive to battle expected water shortages.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Please define CAPM for me.", "answers": ["CAPM (Capital Asset Pricing Model) is a widely used term in finance that describes the relationship between systematic risk and expected return. We can utilize CAPM when pricing risky securities and calculating expected yields. Although CAPM is a widely accepted model, there are some imperfections; however, it's still used a great deal in the finance industry. Briefly show the interviewer that you are familiar with CAPM.", "\"CAPM stands for Capital Asset Pricing Model. CAPM has been helpful for me in the past when it comes time to determine if a security is fairly valued. Although there can be issues with CAPM, the method can help investors understand the relationship between expected risk and reward. This understanding can, in turn, help investors to make better decisions when it comes to adding securities to their portfolio.\"", "\"I understand CAPM to be short for Capital Asset Pricing Model. Although I have not gained a lot of exposure to the model, I do understand that the formula is ERi = Rf + ?i (ERm - Rf). I learned a bit about this and believe it has to do with the expected return of investment, risk-free rate, beta of the investment, expected return of market, and market risk premium.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Where do you see the economy going this year?", "answers": ["Aside from your opinion, the interviewer also wants to see that you spend time getting to know the ever-changing market conditions. Talk about where you think the markets may be going in the next 12 months. Be prepared to discuss where you get your information, or how you have gone about forming your prediction. \n\nMost important here is that you sound well-read and informed, up to date, and engaged. You can talk about stocks and bonds, commodities, and even the global market.", "\"I have read many opinion pieces on The New York Times, The Economist, Investopedia, and more. One common theme that I have found is how the dollar will continue to stabilize throughout the year. The flow of foreign capital into United States assets may slow due to softer monetary policy and a lack of need for new capital for business expansion. This opinion is that of Byron R. Wien, Vice Chairman in the Private Wealth Solutions group at Blackstone, and I happen to agree wholeheartedly.\"", "\"Geopolitical tensions will continue to rise as we see tougher laws on trade. I have read plenty of market predictions from sources such as he Wall Street Journal, Fortune Magazine, and Bloomberg Markets. I believe China's influence will become stronger as the United States continues to isolate itself further.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What can you do for Company ABC that other candidates cannot?", "answers": ["This question is another way of asking, 'Why should we hire you?' The best way to answer this inquiry is to comb through the Company ABC job description and narrow down the most persuasive skills matches. \n\nYou will also want to think about one of your most significant work accomplishments, which other candidates may not have. For instance, this could include awards and accolades, your GPA, additional certifications, or designations. Be prepared to deliver a remarkable credibility statement.", "\"In addition to meeting your requirements for education, experience, and career accomplishments, I will also compliment Company ABC efforts when it comes to diversity and inclusion. I understand that Company ABC believes gender equality is an economic imperative. I will complement Company ABC by supporting women's economic empowerment and leadership opportunities. These efforts will help drive growth for your clients and shareholders.\"", "\"On your Company ABC careers page you speak about how your biggest assets are your people, capital, and your reputation. In addition to the experience I bring in wealth management, as well as the 3.94 GPA I bring from my post-secondary degree, I also promise to help you uphold these business principles every day. I am dedicated to fully complying with the laws, regulations, and the overall spirit of your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "How does Company ABC keep its clients informed on critical finance-related topics?", "answers": ["It is critical to Company ABC that they continually meet the unique needs of their diverse client base. The interviewer wants to see that you have researched the efforts they go to, ensuring that their clients feel informed on important finance-related topics. Be prepared to discuss some of the ways that Company ABC serves their clients.", "\"Your company is well-researched on hot topics in global finance news, ensuring that you remain focused on the short and long term needs of your clients. You remain closely aligned with your clients and shareholders through regular polls, e-newsletters, and market reports. Efforts to reinforce your firms' culture ensure that your clients are always receiving the latest information. I believe that Company ABC starts by investing in employee knowledge so that your team members are more likely to offer a broader depth of knowledge to each client.\"", "\"Hiring people who are interested in solving complex problems is a great start, and one of the ways that Company ABC ensures its clients are always well informed. I understand that you publish many important market reports, lead critical research on global finance topics, and are continually in contact with your clients offering value-adds such as whitepapers, ebooks, newsletter updates, and more.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What are the three most important traits for a high-end wealth management professional to possess?", "answers": ["The traits that you mention should be traits that you possess! Think back to the job posting by Company ABC and if they list any specific soft skills, ideal characteristics, or preferred personality traits. Perhaps on their careers page, or 'about us' section of their website, they make mention of their core philosophies or business values. Be sure to align your response as closely as possible with Company ABC views.", "\"I have read a lot on Company ABC and what it takes to succeed, not only in wealth management but also within your organization. I believe the most critical traits here are flexibility, open-mindedness, and a thirst for education. You invest in the careers of your employees and go to great measures to ensure their interests remain focused on those of your clients and shareholders. I appreciate your goal to maximize individual potential. I also value continued education and learning opportunities.\"", "\"In my opinion, the three most important traits for a high-end wealth management professional include adaptability, an eagerness to learn, and maximum integrity. These are all traits mentioned in the Company ABC website and job posting, showing me that there is strong alignment with our morals and values.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What is your professional mission statement?", "answers": ["Company ABC is a highly esteemed wealth management resource, who has to be sure that every professional they hire is the 'cream of the crop.' Also, they need assurance that your professional manta aligns well with their own. In a sensitive industry such as finance and wealth management, your professional motto is an essential factor to ponder. Think of this question as addressing your credibility statement, ensuring you come across as trustworthy and honest, to your clients, peers, and management.", "\"My professional mantra is to better the lives of every client I come across. My clients need to know that I am 100% concerned with their financial health and completely on board with their long-term vision. It's care over profits.\"", "\"Service, knowledge, and vision. My professional mantra surrounds these three factors. 1. To service my clients before my own needs. 2. To keep my knowledge current and sharp. 3. To be ever-prepared with a short-term and long-term vision for my clients, firm, and career.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "If you helped someone make their first investment, what are the first steps you would take?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see what kind of advice you would give to a new investor. This question, especially if you are a seasoned wealth manager in high-end wealth management, will take you back to the very basics. Give an answer that shows your knowledge but also your ability to guide and teach people who are not as experienced as you may be.", "\"If I were to help someone with their very first investments, I would first remind them that investing can be very simple. I would speak in terms that someone could understand and exercise patience when explaining terms and processes. I would ensure that these persons' finances were in order, so they knew what they could afford to invest every month. Then, I would set some achievable and basic goals.\"", "\"To understand terminology is fundamental, so I would first share some resources so that this new investor understood the industry's language. Then, I would perform a financial health assessment and a risk tolerance assessment. I would ask for their top 3 most important financial goals and what they believed was a reasonable timeline for the achievement of each goal. From there, I would make investment recommendations.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Tell me about your professional designations, and how you aim to further your education in the next three years.", "answers": ["As a professional in the wealth management industry, you most likely have a variety of professional designations to compliment your bachelor's degree, masters' degree, or MBA. The most common designation is a Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) or Chartered Financial Planner (CFP). \n\nTake the time to remind the interviewer of your education and corresponding designations, briefly. Most important to the interviewer is that you show a keen interest in expanding your knowledge for years to come. Your continued education plan could include further developing your expertise in finance, accounting, statistics, or even data analysis.", "\"I have found that so much of my work includes taking a plethora of data and analyzing it to find trends. These trends then help me to make better predictions. In the next three years, I plan to focus my education on courses that include building my quantitative analysis skills. I believe this will complement my MBA, as well as my CFA designation.\"", "\"I recently earned my CFA designation, which I am eager to stack up with my Masters' Degree in Finance. I realize that, as a wealth professional, my education should never stop. For that reason, I have enrolled in two courses this year; Advanced Investment Strategies, and Growth Investing. I plan to take further courses over time, that include data analysis and statistics.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Name for me one significant deal or accomplishment by Company ABC in the last 12 months.", "answers": ["This question speaks directly to how well you have researched Company ABC before attending your interview. Take a look at the company website, their news section, check out Google, and see if they are trending on any topics. \n\nYou do not need to go into a significant amount of detail on what you find. Give enough to show the interviewer that you are paying attention to their organizations' accomplishments.", "\"I read the other day that Company ABC beat expected revenues for Q2 this year, which is amazing news. Your shares closed 1.9% higher, bringing your year-to-date gains to 29%. The fact that Company ABC is blowing away the expectations of analysts worldwide is fascinating to see.\"", "\"I see that Company ABC has made significant strides in the past 12 months on efforts to close the gender investing gap. I appreciate that Company ABC has identified that women-owned businesses often do not get the investments they deserve. I was thrilled to read about your new initiative to invest millions into private, late-stage, women-founded, women-owned, or women-led companies.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Give me an example of someone in the finance industry with a lot of integrity.", "answers": ["The news often delivers stories and examples of finance professionals who are not doing the right thing by their clients. The interviewer at Company ABC wants to talk about the opposite! Finance professionals who have helped to shape your career positively. Think about an influencer or thought leader in the industry who you admire. Be prepared to discuss what you admire most about their approach, and why.", "\"I most admire (person's name). They are one of the most trusted sources I can find when it comes to financial and market data. They have been a go-to name and source as a finance industry analyst for enterprises and independent wealth managers, alike. His weekly e-newsletter is a treasure trove of industry analysis and statistics, which I follow religiously.\"", "\"Hands down, the finance professional I trust and learn from the most is (person's name). She has a multi-national track record of success in the business world. She has started companies in four countries and helped manage businesses in over ten countries. Her career describes the type of finance career I strive to have one day.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What is your favorite resource for wealth-management and finance related news?", "answers": ["You can lean on a multitude of resources in the wealth-management and finance realm. Most importantly, you should show the interviewer that you get your information from the most reputable resources. Talk about one publication that you tune into the most, and be prepared to discuss why it is your go-to resource. If you follow Company ABC sources, you can mention those as well.", "\"I like to know what is being said by the worlds' most prestigious wealth-management firms; including that of Company ABC. For that reason, I read every top firms' blogs, subscribe to newsletters, and follow along on social media. If I had to choose just one favorite resource; however, I would choose The Wall Street Journal because of its reputation and longevity.\"", "\"The Economist has been my go-to resource for many years now. I would read this publication even when I was in high school when my friends were playing video games. What I appreciate about The Economist is that it provides insight into international news, but it's all-encompassing to include politics, business, finance, science, and technology. These topics all work together, so I believe it's important to have a well-rounded view.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "If hired at Company ABC how will you show our clients that you are a trusted resource?", "answers": ["Clients trust Company ABC with billions upon billions of dollars, so they need to know that you are a good fit for their team; carrying the torch of trust! \n\nAs a professional in the wealth management industry, you must be capable of quickly instilling a feeling of confidence in your clients. This trust includes knowing that you are armed with the most up-to-date information, protecting their money and helping them to grow their financial situation. Discuss what you do to show potential clients that you should be their go-to source when it comes to their financial future.", "\"Building client trust begins long before the client officially hires me. Every month I provide my prospects and clients with a free, in-depth market report. I research and write the report myself, ensuring that I am a thought leader and someone they can trust. If big news comes out, I aim to be the first person in their inbox, offering them tips on how to max out their investments. If hired by Company ABC, I will provide immense value to everyone you serve.\"", "\"The fastest way for me to show Company ABC clients that I am a trusted resource is to listen to them. Once I come from a place of complete understanding, knowing exactly their situation, only then will I begin to make recommendations. Then, it's imperative that I make recommendations that empower them to make wise decisions.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What factors most significantly impact the wealth management industry, today?", "answers": ["Company ABC needs to see that you come with a full understanding of the factors that impact their business, industry, and clients. As a professional in the wealth-management industry, you keep up to date with what's happening in global news, and you turn to reputable resources for the latest information. Discuss what you believe to be the most significant factors that are impacting the wealth management industry today.", "\"According to a very intriguing report released recently by Deloitte, there are ten primary factors that impact the wealth management industry. These factors include a higher intensity of competition, increased regulatory burdens, a new generation of investors who think entirely differently, and the introduction of artificial intelligence. These are to name a few. It's important to me that I keep up with these rising trends as they directly impact my career in wealth management and the financial success of my clients.\"", "\"I follow many blogs and publications from companies such as your own, Goldman Sachs, and Morgan Stanley. The factors and topics touched on the most often include previous financial crisis, adapting to quickly changing market environments, shareholder expectations, strict regulations that change often, and milestones in tech. I believe that together, all of these topics shape the wealth management industry in a sometimes unpredictable way.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "At Company ABC you will be presented with new information every day. Talk to me about your preferred learning style.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you best learn, as far as your studying and work styles, how you absorb new information, and how you remain disciplined. Think about your post-secondary education and how you organized, managed and arranged your work. How you answer this question can determine if your learning style will be a match for the training style of Company ABC or even the mentorship style of the person to whom you would be reporting.", "\"I am a visual learner, and I use images to recall information. This learning preference is why Venn diagrams and graphs are so helpful to me when I am taking in data, and new concepts. I like to dive in and become involved in the materials right from the start; which allows me to absorb information much more quickly. While completing my initial CFP designation, I watched a lot of video tutorials online, for instance. This method helped me to commit particular concepts and methods to memory.\"", "\"As a university student, and now as I grow my career, I find that I learn best when I am on the move. I am a high-energy person, so if I can listen to an audiobook while running on the treadmill before work, I can nail a presentation on that book quickly after. I also learn kinetically; for instance, when I was memorizing finance terms in university, I created flashcards for myself. This approach was also very effective.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Have you ever bent or broken any policies to make a client happy?", "answers": ["This question is a blend of both honesty-based, and client-service inquires. Breaking the rules, and bending them can be different from each other. Sometimes, organizations are okay with you bending the rules to keep a client happy; however, in the wealth management and finance industry, this is a very tight rope to walk. You need to know your audience and ensure that you never break any legal obligations in the name of customer service.", "\"We strictly enforce policy and rules in my current company. I understand the need to be very careful when it comes to breaching any laws related to finance, and more. If the policy bent is something like waiving a small administration fee, then I will gain permission from my supervisor before doing so. However, I would not consider breaking a significant policy or legislation to make a client happy. I would work harder to find an alternative solution.\"", "\"I have been trained to know that rules and policy are present for excellent reasons. If I were not sure what to do or were asked to break or bend a rule, I would speak with my management to see what could be done to make the client happy without entering a grey area.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "How would you sell an investment product you did not believe in?", "answers": ["Think carefully before answering because this could be a trick question! Of course, the answer should be that you would never sell an investment product in which you did not believe. The interviewer wants to know that you will uphold the integrity of Company ABC by only promoting products to your clients that you can stand behind.", "\"I can almost always find something positive in a product or service offering; however, that does not mean that I stand behind it. So, in a nutshell, I would not sell an investment product that I would not buy into myself. A great deal of my work, as an advisor, is to uncover those features and draw attention to them, allowing my customer to see the full picture before making investment decisions. I appreciate that Company ABC operates by the same philosophy, which is one of the reasons why I applied to work for you.\"", "\"I would never sell an investment product in which I did not believe. Before making any suggestions to clients, I think about what I would do if it were my financial future. If I feel any tug of hesitation at all, I do further research before bringing the option to the table.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "Are you applying for jobs with any Company ABC direct competitors?", "answers": ["The wealth management industry is a competitive one. It is essential to Company ABC that they understand where you are in your job search, and which roles or companies are most appealing to you. Also, it can make the interviewer and hiring process a bit smoother when Company ABC knows what they need to do to remain competitive. Tell the interviewer about your search so far without disclosing every single detail. It's okay to leave a bit of mystery!", "\"I am in the process of exploring opportunities at wealth management firms that appeal to me; however, I am selective about where my applications go. I am very excited about this particular opportunity with Company ABC and I look forward to the next round of interviews.\"", "\"I have not applied to any other roles at this time but will be taking a closer look at other openings in the next few days. When I heard there was a position open with Company ABC, I had to jump on the opportunity to apply. Your reputation is second-to-none, and I would be thrilled to continue building my portfolio with your esteemed organization.\""]}, {"topic": "High-End+Wealth+Management", "question": "What questions do you have for me on this job, and working for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Not having any questions is not a badge of honor! Many times in interviews, candidates will not have questions prepared, thinking this shows off how well-researched and prepared they are. However, the truth is quite the opposite. By asking a couple of pre-prepared questions, you are showing the interviewer full engagement and interest. Be sure that your queries are not mundane or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a question that is easily answered by simple research. \n\nDig a bit deeper and ask questions such as: \n\n- How has Company ABC embraced FinTech advancements this year? \n- What is your favorite part about working for Company ABC?\n- What is Company ABC biggest goal in the next 12 months? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in the wealth management industry over the next two years? \n- Is there anything from my resume, or our conversation, that I can clarify for you? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking! A couple of questions come to mind. What do you see as the biggest challenge Company ABC will be facing in the next 12 months? Also, what is your wealth manager turnover rate? Lastly, could you tell me about the retention plan you currently have in place for your wealth managers?\"", "\"I would like to ask if there is anything in my work or educational background on which you need clarification? Also, after discussing everything today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this wealth manager role Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Do you consider yourself a creative thinker in the workplace or do you prefer to follow a predetermined set of rules?", "answers": ["Most organizations prefer to hire candidates who can apply creative thinking when needed, but can also follow protocol and guidelines. Assure the interviewer that you are an individual who can achieve both.", "\"In the workplace, I naturally lean towards my preference of straightforward rules and expectations. From there, once I am comfortable in my knowledge base, I can start to think outside of the box. So - to answer your question - I would say I bring a healthy balance of both.\"", "\"I am most comfortable when my creativity is challenged. I like to think of new ways of working, and create alternate solutions to a variety of scenarios. With that said, I am more than capable of following a predetermined set of rules.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Do you prefer to work with clients on their business/commercial insurance needs, or health/life insurance needs? Why?", "answers": ["Some Insurance companies focus solely on commercial/business insurance while others work strictly on health/life insurance. Other insurance companies offer a full suite of services. \n\r\nBefore interviewing with Company ABC be sure that you understand exactly what they offer their clients. Your answer should highlight the ways that the company and your background are a match.", "\"I understand that Company ABC offers a full suite of services to their clients. I have experience working in all types of insurance and am comfortable in most areas. If I had to choose one area of strength I would say that I have a few more years' experience in commercial insurance.\"", "\"Although I do have more experience in health and life insurance, I am very eager to gain more momentum in the area of commercial insurance. The variety, and challenge, would be welcome at this point in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their own particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not a mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "In your most recent position, what was the size of your client portfolio? Was that manageable for you?", "answers": ["If you are interviewing for an account manager or sales related role with Company ABC, have you inquired into the size of portfolio that you are expected to manage? \n\r\nDisclose to the interviewer the size of your current, or most recent, insurance portfolio. Assure them that you are able to handle the volume required of you, should you be offered the position.", "\"With my current company I have a portfolio of $55M which I grew from $15M when I first started. I am comfortable with this volume but can certainly handle more if required. May I ask what the average Insurance agent's book of business looks like with Company ABC?\"", "\"My most recent portfolio was smaller than I would have liked which is why I am seeking a new opportunity. My preference would be to have an active portfolio in the $25-30 million range.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "The Insurance industry boasts new trends and developments quite frequently. How do you stay on top of these changes?", "answers": ["Being 'in-the-know' within the Insurance industry takes dedication as it is an ever-changing landscape. Talk to the interviewer about the ways in which you stay on top of new developments in the Insurance industry.", "\"I find it very exciting to research and study new trends and ideas in the Insurance marketplace. I have a few favorite blogs that I subscribe to. This way, I receive quick updates in my inbox every morning. If I find solid interest, or need clarification on any of the topics, I will research the concept or trend further.\"", "\"In order to stay up to date on insurance industry trends, I subscribe to a variety of google alerts. I am also an avid reader who follows industry influencers. With that said, I love to learn about new resources! Which are your favorite methods of staying on top of industry trends?\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"I do feel that honesty is the best policy so long as the honest comment does not come with the intention of being hurtful.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "What leadership qualities do you possess?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are able to be a great leader, even if your job title does not include formal leadership responsibilities. Talk about a time when you acted as a leader, whether asked or not. \n\nFor example, you may state, \"I feel that I am good at motivating a team.  Last year, I motivated my sales team every day, and we ended up being the top sales team in the company for the year!\"", "\"I feel that I am good at motivating a team.  Last year, I motivated my sales team every day, and we ended up being the top sales team in the company for the year!\"", "Some great qualities of a leader are:\n\n- Being someone who people naturally want to follow\n- Exceptional interpersonal skills\n- Strong relationship building skills\n- Taking ownership for the team's errors and mistakes\n- Excelling at motivating others\n- Providing kudos to your team\n- Knowing how to select and hire the right people to join the team\n- Having a vision for the future"]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "How do you feel globalization has affected the Insurance industry?", "answers": ["Globalization is a business concept that encourages international trade in order to strengthen the economic situation between Countries. Discuss with the interviewer your thoughts on how this practice may be affecting the Insurance industry.", "\"I feel that globalization has forced many companies to be creative and flexible when it comes to their business insurance needs. Namely, companies who now have international offices, hire offshore employees, and who participate in global trade. It has caused the Insurance industry to think outside of the box and has, in my opinion, created some very thought provoking challenges.\"", "\"I think that globalization has made the insurance industry more competitive; thus, creating a greater need for good reviews and customer satisfaction. Customers are better educated and that holds the entire industry more accountable.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "What type of work environment allows you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Are you able to be productive in any environment? Are there particular types of environments that you find distracting? Discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the type of environment that is offered in this position prior to the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative. I come from a similar environment and found that I could be very productive when there was the \"", "\"I work well in a high pressure, demanding environment that requires you to work smart and make your mark.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Tell me about your post-secondary experience and how it prepared you for a career with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that the knowledge you gained during your post-secondary studies is going to be applied here, if you are hired. \n\r\nAssure the interviewer that you have gained transferable knowledge and that you are prepared to apply that knowledge.", "\"Every valuable piece of knowledge gained from my Bachelor of Business Administration Degree will be applied to my work with Company ABC. My University experience was a positive one. I was able to apply myself wholeheartedly and graduate top of my class. In addition to the knowledge gained, I also developed strong organizational skills and a keen ability to multitask; additional skills that I look forward to bringing to Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I do not bring industry specific post-secondary education, I do have some coursework completed that would be transferable to this role with Company ABC. These courses include business administration, portfolio management, and organizational behavior.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Insurance contracts can be detailed and lengthy. How do you help your clients to understand their Insurance contract?", "answers": ["No matter which Insurance company you work for, the client contracts and policies will likely be full of detail and be difficult to understand, for the typical layman. \n\r\nTake the interviewer through your process when it comes to explaining contracts and policies to your customers. Assure the interviewer that your communication skills are solid.", "\"I understand that insurance policies and contracts can appear complicated to my clients. I will walk them through each section, before they sign, and use simpler terms and analogies when needed. I have often had clients comment on my ability to relay the information to them in an easy to understand method.\"", "\"Yes, insurance contracts can absolutely be difficult to understand! I do not want to assume that a client is struggling so I will let them go through the contract on their own pace and then encourage questions through all steps in the process.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Have you obtained any Insurance related certifications or licenses?", "answers": ["Some positions within Company ABC will require you to hold special certification or licensing. These requirements may be different depending on the State that you are working in as well. Talk to the interviewer about any additional certifications you may hold and be sure to ask about their expectations and needs.", "\"In 2009 I completed my Certificate in General Insurance through the Insurance Institute of America (IIA). I am currently completing my Associate in Insurance Services (AIS) certificate. Are there any other certificates or licenses required to work in this role?\"", "\"I am newer to this industry and just recently completed the Insurance Claims Training Course through FEMA. Are there any courses that you suggest I take immediately? I want to be well prepared for career growth at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Have you ever worked in a cross-functional environment?", "answers": ["If you work for a larger company, you may have been asked to work on a project with teams from another department. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a big asset to your potential employer, especially if they are a larger organization. \n\nMaybe you headed a project which required you to collaborate with the members from the engineering and sales teams. You may have had the opportunity to organize a volunteer activity or team building exercise, company-wide. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"I am regularly exposed to cross-functional teamwork in my current position. I believe that when expectations are communicated clearly from the beginning, a cross-functional team project can be very successful. I go into these types of projects with an understanding that everyone has their own strengths and limitations based on their expertise and job function.\"", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. Primarily with the HR department and the Accounting department. Clear communication is key when collaborating with different teams. Clarity in expectations is of huge importance.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "How would you describe your relationship with your customers or clients?", "answers": ["Do you value your client and customer relationships? How do you nurture them to ensure that they are happy and continue to come back? Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for strong customer and client relationships.", "\"My customer and client relationships are best described as open and honest. I believe that the more upfront and transparent you are with your clients, the more likely they are to return. I most definitely value my clients and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"My customer and client relationships are most important to me. A happy client is a client that will help me to achieve my targets and goals. Happy clients offer referrals and give you their business because you have developed a great amount of trust with them. My client relationships can best  be described as valued, nurtured, and well-crafted.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "When it comes to Insurance, would you rather work face to face with clients, or in the background in a research and analysis based role?", "answers": ["After researching Company ABC, do you feel that they have a strong reputation based around customer relationship? Talk to the interviewer about your preference around number crunching vs. customer facing. No matter your preference, be sure to highlight your ability to be a proud face of the company.", "\"I am more of an analyst type and do prefer to be in the background, making the numbers happen. With that said; I am still a people person and would always put my best face forward in any customer facing situation.\"", "\"I am definitely more of a face to face communicator. I love being in the buzz of it all and I thrive in customer facing situations. I am also able to work in the background, when needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire individuals with longevity in mind. Where do you see your career 5 years from now?", "answers": ["Interviewing, vetting, and hiring a new team member is an expensive and time consuming effort for any company. Assure the interviewer that if you were hired on with Company ABC that you plan to stay long term.", "\"As you can see on my resume, I have strong tenure with my previous employers. I would love nothing more than to find a long-term home where I can naturally grow. Over the next 5 years I would love to be promoted within Company ABC as I prove my strengths and abilities.\"", "\"In 5 years I would like to see myself as part of your executive team. I would also like to see the size of my portfolio triple in value from where it is today.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Since beginning your career in Insurance, what do you feel has been the most significant industry change?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your thoughts on change within the Insurance industry. This is a perfect opportunity to display your passion and insight when it comes to your industry. Be sure to keep your answer in a positive and conversational tone as opposed to heavily opinionated.", "\"The biggest change that I have seen in the Insurance industry, since my start in 1999, has to do with technology. There are so many great mobile trends now; including apps that make information simple and easy to access. it's been incredible to see.\"", "\"I would say that the most significant change to the insurance industry, since I joined the industry, has been technology and the changes that come with it. The industry has become more competitive because of it. With that said, I encourage the competition because it keeps most people in the industry honest, and encourages us all to try harder for our clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Within Company ABC many of our positions require a Bachelors or Masters Degree. Have you considered furthering your education in order to advance your career?", "answers": ["While it may not be required for all positions, some roles within Company ABC may require a higher post-secondary education. Talk to the interviewer about your willingness to expand on your post-secondary education.", "\"I currently have a Bachelors Degree in Business Administration and have considered completing my MBA through online coursework on the weekends and evenings. If a Masters Degree is required to reach particular levels with Company ABC then I am happy to do so.\"", "\"I am always open to additional training and coursework. Since I already have my MBA, I would not return to full time studies; however, if there is a course you recommend, I would be happy to attend.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": ["We all like to be recognized in some way for our accomplishments in the workplace. Share with the interviewer how you would like to be recognized for your hard work. Through gifts? Financial perks? Public recognition? Kind words? Title promotions?", "\"I am very much an over-achiever and find that the best way for me to be recognized for a job well done is to be given words of kindness and recognition. I am easily encouraged and the best reward for me is to know that my hard work is being noticed.\"", "\"I do not particularly love public recognition so I would say that the best way to recognize me for my accomplishments would be an increase in responsibilities and continued autonomy.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "When have you had to think quickly in response to sudden change?", "answers": ["Sudden changes will occur in the workplace from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of responding quickly, and professionally, to sudden changes in the workplace.", "\"I am able to think quickly on the job and I do respond well to sudden change. Last week I was asked to tweak a presentation with just 30 minutes notice. The changes were significant but luckily I work well under pressure. The presentation went well and our clients were very happy.\"", "\"The insurance industry can be quite volatile so I would suggest that I think quickly in response to change, multiple times per day. When I do need to pivot quickly, I do so in a safe and calculated way that can benefit all parties.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8 because I value communication but, just like most people, I have things to learn. Some ways that I ensure clear communication are by utilizing multiple methods of delivering messages and I give ample time for questions before implementing changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Tell me about an error or mistake you made because of a breakdown in communication from you or one of your team members.", "answers": ["On occasion, mistakes will happen and communication will be broken. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this occurred in the workplace. How did you resolve the situation?", "\"I recall one instance where I misread an email from one of my subordinates. The punctuation was incorrect and I read it in a dire tone rather than in a positive one, as it was intended. After a tense conversation, the employee clarified her intention and it seems I was mistaken. She and I agreed to exercise verbal communication on a regular basis to avoid a similar situation from happening again.\"", "\"I had a manager text me one time about a client who was not happy with the results of my work. I was really upset, because I try my best at all times, and felt that the conversation would have been better delivered to me in-person. The next day, I approached the manager and requested that future communication of that nature be conducted in person, versus text message. I did apologize for my initially defensive reaction.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "What do you know about the culture at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Before you interview with Company ABC it is very important that you do your research. This includes scanning the company website, checking for online customer reviews, going to Glassdoor.com to view any employee reviews, and perhaps speaking to anyone you know who already works in the company. Display to the interviewer that you are engaged in the interview process by doing your 'homework; on them.", "\"I have researched Company ABC a great deal and have found that your company maintains a strong focus on a family based atmosphere, even through your growth mode. I appreciate that your company rewards employee dedication through career growth and educational opportunities.\"", "\"Your company has a really impressive industry reputation and I would be thrilled to learn from your leadership team. From my research I find that you are very involved in the community and put a lot of efforts into developing your employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "How do you respond to feedback?", "answers": ["Receiving feedback from a manager or supervisor can be tough. You can't always predict what they may say, and you also can't always predict how you might feel in response. Learning how to respond when given a performance review or negative feedback is important.", "\"Even though it can be difficult to hear criticism, I always pause before I respond and take time to think about it first. If it's something that catches me by surprise, I usually ask if they can clarify or explain. I want to grow and improve so the more specific my supervisor can be, the more helpful it is.\"", "\"I love receiving feedback from my employer because the feedback allows me to better understand where I need to improve.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "When have you shown great integrity at work?", "answers": ["Integrity is best displayed through honesty and consistent moral values. Talk to the interviewer about the   way(s) that you show your integrity in the workplace.", "\"In my last position, I was responsible for the cash deposit on a daily basis. There was never a discrepancy, in the 4 years that I worked there. I best show my integrity by being a consistently reliable employee.\"", "\"I show integrity at work all of the time. It's an incredibly important thing, to consistently show excellence through integrity. In the workplace,  I show integrity by keeping my promises, earning and keeping the trust of my colleagues, and avoiding all workplace gossip.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations are to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000 and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "Do you feel performance should be rewarded over experience?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you should be paid based on tenure, or results? Discuss this with the interviewer and back your answer with an example, if possible.", "\"I feel that employees should be paid, and rewarded, based on their performance. A new employee would be greatly motivated through being rewarded for performance and it encourages a healthy competition with tenured employees.\"", "\"I feel both performance and experience should be equally rewarded and weighted.\""]}, {"topic": "Insurance", "question": "How often do you take work home with you?", "answers": ["The majority of people will work overtime hours or take work home with them on occasion. Talk to the interviewer about how frequently to take your work home.", "\"I make sure to utilize my work hours very efficiently so the only time that I take my work home is when there is an extremely stringent deadline. I would say that, overall, I take my work home maybe twice per month. It's all about being diligent with your time in the office!\"", "\"I will take my work home with me anytime I feel that a deadline may be close. I would much rather work overtime hours than let a client down.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Wealth management is an all encompassing term. How would you explain what we do at Company ABC to someone unfamiliar with our company?", "answers": ["The term 'wealth management' can become fuzzy as there are many interpretations, along with a plethora of companies that offer wealth and financial investment services and products. The interviewer wants to see that you have conducted ample research on Company ABC. Briefly discuss what you understand Company ABC to do, in a way that anyone outside of the industry could follow.", "\"For someone who is not familiar with Company ABC or even the term wealth management, I would describe the services as services for the affluent that include financial planning, portfolio management, and investment guidance. From research, I understand that the top products offered at Company ABC include (A), (B), and (C) which fall into these categories.\"", "\"The easiest way to understand wealth management, and what you do at Company ABC is the structured management of money, for those who are affluent, conscious about making their money work for them and conscious of planning for life's milestones such as retirement.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Analytical skills are critical to success as a Financial Advisor. In which ways are you analytically minded?", "answers": ["There are many ways to show that you are analytically minded. Perhaps you are great with research or investigating a problem. Maybe you take clear and logical steps in everything that you do. Or, you show a methodical or clear-cut approach to reaching your goals and completing tasks. Be prepared to discuss how you are analytically minded, making you an exceptional professional in the wealth management industry.", "\"As a Financial Advisor, I use my analytical skills when detecting patterns in finance trends, observing and interpreting data, theorizing on where the market is going, or brainstorming ideas for my clients when their decisions lean on multiple factors and options available in the market. I take pride in my analytical abilities because they help me to do my job exceptionally well while also benefitting my clients greatly.\"", "\"My analytical skills are getting stronger every day, and I had the opportunity to hone in on them during my time in university. In school, I would collect and analyze information, problem-solve, and make decisions based on data. I will bring my analytical strengths to Company ABC to help you solve problems and ensure your clients see the most financial success possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How do you deal with client rejection or objections?", "answers": ["Part of working in wealth management is sales and, what comes with sales, is facing rejection and objections regularly. Talk to the interviewer about any formal training you have in objection handling. Be prepared to discuss how you handle, and bounce back from, rejection.", "\"I love the quote by Tom Hopkins that says, 'Begin always expecting good things to happen.' This quote encompasses my approach to sales and even client rejection. I know that my offering is better than the rest, and I stand behind my work and maintain integrity in everything that I do. The 'right' client for me is one that will see these qualities right away and be willing to hear me out, at the very least. When I hear the word 'no,' I understand 'not right now.' No is not forever, and I will continue to massage even the 'no' relationships until they turn into a yes!\"", "\"To be a successful professional in the wealth management industry, I must rely on my reputation, referrals from others, and professional follow up. For these reasons, no matter how a customer rejection might make me feel, I vow to remain professional. I am a positive person by nature, so I when rejection comes my way, I will ask more questions to see if I can find the true source of the objection.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Financial Advisors with Company ABC who are active in their community see more success. Tell me about an organization or group outside of work with which you are involved.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are giving of your time and involved in your community. As a Financial Advisor, a lot of your success comes from networking and getting your name out into the community.  Volunteer work and community involvement showcase strong character and selflessness, which are all qualities that make a great advisor. Talk to the interviewer about how you are active and involved outside of work.", "\"I recently began sitting on the business commerce board for our city. Part of what we do it raise funds for local schools and other needs for the community, while also providing helpful resources to local business owners. I have thoroughly enjoyed my experience so far and plan to dedicate myself more often to giving back to others.\"", "\"Aside from being a Financial Advisor, I am also the parent of three young children. Their schools and sports groups are often running community fundraising events. This year I volunteered to be a school committee treasurer. It doesn't take up much of my time, but it does feel great to be an active parent helper.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Many Company ABC employees work as though they are independent business owners. Talk to me about what makes your entrepreneurial by nature.", "answers": ["Although you may be employed by Company ABC, they want to ensure that you will be able to run your portfolio as though it is your own business. You may be responsible for building your client list, maintaining relationships, and adjusting your business to the ever-changing economic environments and trends that we face today. \n\nShare with the interviewer what an entrepreneurial mindset means to you, and how you go about exercising that mentality in your day to day work.", "\"For me, it's important that I continue to manage my portfolio of clients as though it's my own business. To do this, I pay for and attend industry conferences regularly. Rather than running straight to management, I reverse engineer problems and conduct research when an issue arises. Also, I take the opportunity to read as much as I can. I absorb myself wholly in topics related to finance, investments, and wealth management.\"", "\"An entrepreneurial mindset, to me, means to continually seek out new challenges and think about my career vision every day. Also, I am an exceptional problem solver. I think quickly and can get myself out of most situations by looking at the issue from various angles. I willingly accept feedback and criticism, then take that feedback to find new ways of working. These are just some of the entrepreneurial qualities I will bring to Company ABC and my clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "What skills did you learn in your current role that will help you succeed at Company ABC?", "answers": ["To answer this question successfully, it's a great idea to take a look back at the job posting or job description, and take note of the skills that Company ABC seems to request the most. \n\nMany job postings are repetitive, and you should be able to see which skills come up more than once or twice. Focus on those keywords when answering this question.", "\"I have learned a great deal from my current organization, and have gained many valuable new skills. I noticed in the Company ABC job posting that you are seeking someone with solid results in cold calling, gaining referrals and networking. These are skills that I have worked very hard to master over the past few years. I make around 100 cold calls per week, and my referral rate is well above 40%; nearly double that of my co-workers. These are just some of the skills that will help me to succeed with Company ABC.\"", "\"During my internship, I learned a lot about the art of conversation and getting to know clients by asking the right questions and being unafraid to dig deeper. In your job posting, you mention looking for a junior advisor who is curious by nature, knows how to ask the best discovery questions, and is great with research. These are just some of the skills I have recently developed, and I am eager to apply them in this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you have experience preparing and delivering presentations?", "answers": ["Part of what you may be expected to do at Company ABC could be planning, preparing, and delivering presentations to clients or other stakeholders. As most of us know, public speaking can be intimidating, causing fear in a lot of people. It's okay to be nervous; however, the interviewer wants to see that these nerves do not get in the way of your preparation and ability to communicate well. \n\nIf applicable, discuss any courses or training you have taken, related to public speaking and presentations. Assure the interviewer that you are capable by reviewing times in the past when you have prepared and given presentations. Be sure to include details such as the topic, what the setting was, and how many people you presented to.", "\"In my current role, I regularly present to my clients, and my team of 20 advisors. To help me gain confidence as a speaker and presenter, I became a Toastmasters member two years ago. Since joining, I have taken courses such as 'The Better Speaker' series, 'Beginning Your Speech,' and 'Concluding Your Speech.' I also have training in PowerPoint, ensuring that my presentations are visually engaging.\"", "\"The bulk of my presentation experience comes from my time in university, where I prepared a variety of speeches and decks. I am a confident public speaker and was able to present to a group of my peers without any issues. I look forward to gaining even more experience in preparing and delivering professional presentations for clients and internal stakeholders.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "This role with Company ABC is very independent. How do you prospect for new customers?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like you to take them through your prospecting process. Because this question is open-ended, it can be easy to go on and on about every small step that you take. The primary purpose is to show the interviewer that you keep yourself organized and have a well thought out approach to building your business. Keep your answer on track while bringing your process to life!", "\"I have a few very effective techniques when it comes to prospecting for new customers. First, I make sure that all of my prospects are in my CRM so that I never skip a beat. I ask for referrals from all of my clients and make warm calls from that list. More passively, I write a lot of wealth management content and publish it on LinkedIn, positioning me as a thought leader and getting my name out there. I gain a lot of leads from this approach. Another highly effective prospecting technique has been attending networking events and joining my city's commerce board.\"", "\"As I build my business as a new financial advisor, it's important that I get my name out there through networking and getting to know people in my community. I volunteer a lot and attend many commerce meetings, which gives me exposure to new people and potential clients. I do a lot of social media marketing in the form of educational posts, which starts conversations online with prospective customers that I may not otherwise meet in person. I also spend time warm calling from my LinkedIn connections.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How do you stay current on developments and trends in wealth management?", "answers": ["There are many resources in the wealth management industry, but the interviewer needs to know that you follow and take advice from only the best. In an online world where you can find any information you need, how do you ensure that your industry knowledge is built from solid resources? Mention the reputable publications that you lean on and feel free to ask the interviewer for a recommendation, too! Asking for recommendations could break the ice and open up a helpful conversation.", "\"I rely on a variety of resources to ensure that I get a broad scope of opinion and information. The sources that I rely on most include opinion pieces published on LinkedIn by my professional network, as well as online publications such as The Economist and Financial Advisor Magazine. If you have some resources to recommend, I would love to hear!\"", "\"The resources that I am most familiar with include Kiplinger, Forbes, and The Financial Advisor Magazine. It's important to me, as I grow my career in wealth management that I remain in-the-know but only through highly reputable resources. I am all ears if you have any reading and resource recommendations.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you have your Certified Financial Planner (CFP) designation? If not, is this something you would like to achieve?", "answers": ["Being a Certified Financial Planner (this may be called something else in your region) is a prestigious designation because it shows your clients that you can meet their needs despite the evolving requirements in the financial planning realm. During your certification, you take a plethora of topics including financial analysis, retirement plans, education, and disability plans, economics, credit and debt, investments, law, insurance, and more. \n\nIf you already possess industry certification(s) that is great! Take the time to discuss what you learned and express the importance of continued education. \n\nIf you are not yet certified, be sure to let the interviewer know that gaining further industry designations is in your short-term career.", "\"I believe it's imperative to be part of a national or federal body that educates and designated professionals in the wealth management industry. I am a certified financial planner and do enjoy the benefits of having the CFP letters behind my name. They signify trust and knowledge, which are two things for which an investor should always look. I will continue to educate myself, past the CFP designation as my career goes on.\"", "\"I have registered for my first information session and plan to earn my CFP designation in the next 2.5 years; once my application is approved by the board. I look forward to offering additional knowledge to my clients, and this designation is an important first step.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "As a wealth management professional, have you ever been asked to act unethically? If so, what did you do?", "answers": ["It's no secret that unethical behavior in the finance industry is widespread. Every day of the week, we hear in the news of somebody new facing fines and jail time for financial crime. \n\nCompany ABC takes pride in their reputation and part of maintaining this reputation means ensuring those they hire are operating entirely above board. If you have ever been asked to act unethically, talk about the situation without speaking poorly of another finance professional, or past employer. If this situation has never happened to you, that's great! Take a minute to assure the interviewer that you will always act with the utmost integrity.", "\"In my career, I have been offered gifts from clients, and although this is not a direct crime, it never feels right to accept anything lavish from a client. I do everything that I can to keep my relationships strictly professional. You can rest assured that I would act with utmost honesty and integrity, representing Company ABC with pride every day.\"", "\"I am newer to my career and have never encountered a situation that rode a grey line. I would never do anything to jeopardize my company, career, or professional reputation. Should a situation be serious, I would report it to my employer or governing board immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How would you build a relationship with a client with an intimidating nature?", "answers": ["In the wealth management industry, you will come across many personalities; some which may be intimidating or come off strong by nature. The interviewer wants to see that you have the smarts, and maturity to deal with strong personalities while maintaining control and professionalism. If you have come across a situation like this, discuss what you did to overcome any feelings of intimidation.", "\"Many of my clients are wealthy business professionals who are busy and do not have a lot of time to fuss around conversations. Sometimes they can come across as intimidating; however, I remind myself that they have a lot on the go, and I need to make every conversation count. I am proud of the work that I deliver, and I stand behind it, no matter how intimidating or brief a client can be.\"", "\"Because of the vulnerable nature of wealth planning and management, I can understand how some people may feel intimidated by the whole thing; thus, coming across a bit harsh or intimidating themselves. If this situation occurs, I will focus less on how I am feeling and more about how they are feeling.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "As a Financial Advisor, your compensation is tied directly to your productivity. How do you feel about working in a highly commissioned role?", "answers": ["Working on a commission-based position is not for everyone! Depending on the structure at Company ABC and the role you are taking on, you may have a base pay, work on a guarantee, or be completely reliant only on the commissions you earn as a Financial Advisor. The interviewer wants to see that you have confidence in your abilities and the strength of your portfolio.", "\"I have worked in a commission-driven environment inside and outside of the wealth management industry. I have made a fantastic living doing so because I believe in my capabilities, I reach my goals, and I keep the promises that I make to myself and my clients.\"", "\"Commission-driven environments are new to me; however, I like the idea that I earn money based on how hard I work. I am not afraid of hard work, so, for that reason, I believe I can flourish in a highly commissioned role.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Company ABC is client-centric. How do you continually strengthen relationships with your exciting client base?", "answers": ["Many employees in the wealth management industry are commission-based and rely on excellent relationships with their client base to make a healthy wage. For these reasons, it's in your best interest to have a solid strategy when it comes to building strong relationships with new clients and building upon your existing client base at the same time. Discuss some steps that you take to ensure you have profitable client relationships.", "\"It's important to me that I take time out of every day to strengthen relationships with my prospective customers as well as my existing client base. For me, it's all about adding value to my offering. This value could be in the form of my monthly newsletters, or the market reports that I publish quarterly. I spend the time to craft interesting downloads, whitepapers, and other PDFs focused on educating my contacts. This way, they become more comfortable with me and being to see me as a thought leader in wealth management. In turn, because of these frequent touchpoints, I am often the first name they think of when they are ready to build a stronger financial future.\"", "\"I think that one of the keys to client connection, as a Financial Advisor, is to have an approachable, professional brand. I learned in business school that humanizing your brand was essential for client engagement. Everyone wants to feel a connection with their advisor, and one built on trust and loyalty. I plan to approach client engagement in a hands-on manner that includes as many phone calls, follow-ups, and in-person meetings as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "In an initial client meeting, how do you first assess a client's financial position?", "answers": ["When it comes to a clients' financial position, and their financial risk tolerance, it's imperative that you, as a wealth management professional, know how to accurately and carefully assess their actual financial status. Show the interviewer at Company ABC that you can take the appropriate steps when first meeting or onboarding a new client.", "\"As a responsible wealth management professional it is essential to me that my clients know their bandwidth when it comes to the risk they are willing to take, and where they want to be in the near, and far future. I saw a lot of pain during the economic downturn as so many investors over-estimated their ability to stomach the risk and the downside of investing. When first assessing a clients' actual financial position, I ask a lot of discovery questions. I also perform time horizon tests such as NestEgg Estimates and other stress tests to ensure they understand where they are as far as their financial future and the risk they are willing to take.\"", "\"There are many ways to assess my client's financial position. I am analytically minded and know that the truth is always in the numbers, so I rely on a lot of data that comes from stress and tolerance tests. I ask a lot of questions regarding future planning and their level of comfortability when it comes to risk. Everyone is different, and it's critical that I treat each client as a unique case.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Walk me through your education and how it relates to a career in wealth management.", "answers": ["Your formal education and industry training might be on your resume; however, the interviewer would like you to dig deeper and bring this education to life for them by discussing how your education has prepared you for this job with Company ABC. \n\nIf you have a finance-specific post-secondary degree, this answer will be straightforward for you. You can list completed coursework applicable to the products and services offered at Company ABC. \n\nIf you do not have an applicable degree, it's time to think about what you learned at your highest levels of education and how that knowledge applies (or will apply) to your work. Some of these skills could include: \n\n- Proposal Writing\n- Public Speaking\n- Presentation Building\n- Independent Learning\n- Academic Research", "\"I earned my masters' degree in finance from ABC University. My degree exposed me to the financial world and specific topics such as bonds, econometrics, economics, corporate finance, governmental finance, individual investment, statistics, and portfolio management. I am grateful for my education and how well it has supported me in my career.\"", "\"I will never be finished when it comes to my education and learning. Although my degree is in business administration, and not specifically finance, my school did prepare me very well for a career in wealth management. I took courses in economics, finance, management, and marketing; all important facets of wealth management.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How would you explain mutual funds to someone unfamiliar with the concept?", "answers": ["Mutual funds may be a basic concept to you, as a wealth management professional; however, the point of the question is for the interviewer to determine how well you can explain financial products to your clients. \n\nCompany ABC has a reputation for educating their clients, helping them to understand common concepts in wealth management better. Show the interviewer that you can deliver these expectations by simply and clearly describing what mutual funds are, being sure to highlight the benefits.", "\"I understand that the world of wealth management can be overwhelming and complicated, which is why it's imperative that I can explain concepts and products very simply. All a client wants to know is if the product is right for them, why it's right, and what kind of results they can expect. For that reason, I would explain mutual funds as a professionally managed money pool. The money pool is used to purchase securities, ideally resulting in a financial return for every investor.\"", "\"Mutual funds are a basic financial concept, so it's important that every one of my clients has a solid idea on how they work. I would tell a client that when they buy a mutual fund, they are pooling their money with many other investors. This pooled money lets them invest more widely for a lower cost. A professional manager decides where to invest this money pool. Mutual funds are flexible, allowing a client to buy or sell their funds at any time.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Tell me about the systems and tools that you lean on to do your job.", "answers": ["If Company ABC mentions any tools or tech in their job posting, be prepared to discuss your exposure to those during your interview. Perhaps they use a specific CRM or tech to help analyze trends in the financial market. Talk to the interviewer about the tools that you currently use, and others that you have used in the past. If you are new to your career, you can talk about any programs that you used in university or during your internship. Be sure to show the interviewer that you are eager and willing to learn.", "\"First and foremost, I use my CRM all day long, and rely heavily on it when it comes to my pipeline of business and existing client portfolio. I use Capsule because it's a CRM that allows me to share progress with my team, should we be working on larger investment accounts together. Aside from my CRM, I also use email marketing automation software, allowing me to keep my leads warm with an email funnel that I have automated. A new tool that I love is NestEgg Estimator, which is a Google app that takes my client's finances and breaks them down into income, taxes, assets, and debt, better helping me to calculate their needs for retirement. The app allows me to play out various scenarios, such as changes in job, expenses, and spending.\"", "\"I have been teaching myself a few new tools, in anticipation for my first job in wealth management. These tools include Salesforce CRM, where I have been taking their free webinars and tutorials. I have used YouTube channels to learn additional tech such as Black Diamond, which is a cloud-based portfolio management platform. I understand that Black Diamond will help me with information aggregation, customizing reports, and other tasks required of me as a junior advisor.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you prefer to work independently, or with partners?", "answers": ["This teamwork-based question will give the interviewer an idea of your preferred work style. The way you answer this question will show a bit about your personality and how you interact with others. You may work well without the need for much direction and collaboration, or maybe you are very driven by a collaborative and team-focused environment. Either way, be honest with the interviewer about your preferences without leaning negatively, either way.", "\"I understand that this role requires me to work both independently and with the partners and team at Company ABC. In my current role, I work independently around 75% of the time, and I do appreciate the autonomy. With that said, around 25% of the time when I am collaborating with the team, I feel encouraged, challenged, and refreshed. It's great to have a balance of independence and teamwork.\"", "\"Being newer to my career, the more I can learn from partners and teammates, the better I will become in my career. So, although I can certainly work on independent tasks, I do prefer at this time to have more interaction with others, giving me opportunities to learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How do you show potential clients that you are a trusted source for information on wealth management and other financial topics?", "answers": ["It's crucial, as an advisor or professional in the wealth management industry, that you can instill a feeling of confidence in your clients. Your clients have to be able to trust that you are in-the-know and that you do everything you can to provide them with the most up-to-date information, protecting their money and helping them to grow their financial situation. Discuss what you do to show potential clients that you should be their go-to source when it comes to their financial future.", "\"For me, as a wealth management professional, it's most important that I show my clients the value they would receive from working with me, long before they officially hire me. Every quarter, I provide my clients, and prospects alike, with an in-depth market report. I research and write the report myself, ensuring that I am a thought leader and someone they can trust. If big news comes out, I aim to be the first person in the inbox, offering them tips and tricks on how to max out their investments.\"", "\"Showing that I am with them every step of the way is crucial. I will give reading recommendations to my prospective clients and do everything I can to empower them. When a potential client sees that I am looking out for them, even when they haven't committed to working with me yet, I bring trust and value to the equation.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Which factors do you believe most impact the growth of the wealth management industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like assurance that you understand how the wealth management industry works, and the factors that could impact your success at Company ABC. Be prepared to discuss any items you have recently read in the news, or talk about the sources that you turn to when you are looking for reliable and up-to-date information on what the wealth management industry is doing.", "\"I follow many blogs and publications from companies such as your own, JP Morgan, and Wells Fargo. The factors and topics touched on the most often include previous financial crisis, adapting to quickly changing market environments, shareholder expectations, strict regulations that change often, and milestones in tech. I believe that together, all of these topics shape the wealth management industry in a sometimes unpredictable way.\"", "\"According to a very intriguing report released recently by Deloitte, there are ten primary factors that impact the wealth management industry. These include a higher intensity of competition, increased regulatory burdens, a new generation of investors who think entirely differently, and the introduction of artificial intelligence and machine learning into the wealth management industry. These are to name a few. It's important to me that I keep up with these rising trends as they directly impact my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "When you suffer a setback in your portfolio, how does that emotionally affect you?", "answers": ["Working in wealth management can be a bumpy ride, as you build your portfolio, and as rules and regulations in the finance industry shift. For this reason, the interviewer at Company ABC would like to know that you can handle the ups and downs of the industry. Be prepared to discuss how setbacks impact you emotionally and how you typically cope.", "\"As a commission-driven Financial Advisor, I am competitive with myself, my past performance, and hyper-targeted when it comes to achieving my goals. I become internally frustrated when I do not meet my goals or a 'done deal' with a client falls through. When this happens, I do a rundown of what I could have done differently, trying to pinpoint where things could have gone wrong. I aim to learn from the situation so that it doesn't hold me back again.\"", "\"I allow myself a moment to be frustrated when a setback occurs, but never in front of a client or colleague. I am very good at keeping my cool and maintaining positive energy. I've lost clients before, from what I perceived to be closed business, and it sometimes hurts, especially financially; however, I never let a situation like that hold me back. In fact, setbacks fuel me to work even harder the second time around.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Why do you want to work in wealth management, and where would you like your career to take you?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know what stems your passion for a career in wealth management. Talk a bit about your history in the industry, how your post-secondary education propelled you into this career, or perhaps how your own experience with a Financial Advisor piqued your interest. \n\nNext, think about where you want to grow with Company ABC. Take a look at the natural career path, from the role you are currently interviewing for, and up a few steps. Do you have ambitions to step up with Company ABC and earn a title promotion? Discuss where you want your career to take you, being sure to show enthusiasm for potential job promotions and opportunity.", "\"I obtained my masters' degree in finance thinking that I would be joining a corporate banking environment. That is until I met a seasoned financial investment advisor who shared with me her career path and successes. I loved the flexibility that she had in her career and that her income potential was never capped like mine would be in a corporate environment. It was history from there! Today, I would like to grow my career to include branch management or a regional position for Company ABC. \"", "\"Growing up, my parents were always teaching me about planning for my financial future, so I believe the seed of interest was planted with me very early. I have a keen interest in making investment suggestions to help people create a sound financial plan. During university, I was the go-to person for other students who wanted to become involved in penny stocks, and from there, my interest flourished. As a recent finance graduate, I am ready to start my career as a junior advisor and work my way into a senior advisory role with Company ABC when the time is right.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "How will your skills complement Company ABC, if hired?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how your skills will benefit Company ABC, should they choose to hire you. This question is an excellent opportunity to highlight the hard skills and soft skills that make you a stand out candidate. Be sure that you answer aligns nicely with the values and mission statement of the organization.", "\"I understand, after reading through your company website, that your mission is to help your clients achieve financial independence and freedom in retirement. My skills in retirement planning are strong, and my portfolio of work attests to this fact. I care about my clients in a way that they notice, which is why I gain such a high referral rate year after year. Lastly, because I have twelve years' experience in the wealth management industry, the time to train me will be significantly reduced, ensuring that I begin making a positive financial impact on Company ABC right away.\"", "\"I am highly technical and analytical and pick up on numbers and systems very quickly. I have already crafted a 30, 60, and 90-day plan to exceed my training expectations and targets. The plan includes doubling up on my cold calls and booking more in-person client meetings. These activities, along with my speed and eagerness, will ensure that I make an impact on the Company ABC bottom-line as soon as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Name for me what you believe to be the biggest challenge facing the wealth management industry today.", "answers": ["The interviewer at Company ABC wants to see that you've conducted ample research on the wealth management industry, and the challenges they face today. Whether you're a seasoned financial planning professional, fresh-faced in your first role outside of university, or even transitioning to a new industry, it's essential that you know the challenging side of the trade before joining. \n\nShare what you believe to be a significant challenge in the wealth management industry today, and why. Bonus points if you have a plan prepared on how you will overcome this challenge!", "\"I believe that one of the biggest challenges that the finance and wealth management industries face today is cybercrime in the form of data breaches and fraud. I recently read that financial cybercrime has increased by almost 500% over the last two years, causing a lot of distrust between customers and their financial service firms. To combat this, I always send a copy of our data security action plan and agreement to my customers, ensuring they have a full understanding of what my firm and I do, to keep their information safe and secure.\"", "\"From what I have read, and researched, FinTech companies are going to become even bigger and fiercer competitors to traditional financial and wealth management firms. I believe it's important that we begin to look at partnering with these tech-savvy startups rather than completely opposing them.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Would you cold call for a year if it meant you had a steady client list afterward?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants assurance that you are willing to put in the hard work required, to later reap the rewards of a stable pipeline of business. Wealth management professionals often focus on the size of their portfolios or the value of their client list; however, you know those results do not come without a ton of leg work. \n\nShow the interviewer that you understand a lucrative career comes from hard work. If you currently spend a lot of time cold calling, prospecting, and working on developing new business opportunities, you can discuss those activities.", "\"I am more than willing to put in time and sweat equity into building my book of business via cold calling; My years of experience in client development within wealth management gives me a good amount of latitude; however, I will never stop trying. I am fully prepared to roll up my sleeves and make many cold calls as needed to maximize my success.\"", "\"I thoroughly enjoy meeting and connecting with people, and I love the idea of getting them to say yes, even when they weren't initially inclined to say no! I cannot expect success to be handed to me overnight. So, yes, I'd be willing to cold call for a year to catapult my career. Upfront investment in the long-term health of my job is an approach that I can get behind.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Have you ever broken a non-disclosure, privacy, or confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["As a professional in the wealth management industry, you will be privy to a lot of sensitive or confidential information on your clients and Company ABC. It is highly likely that Company ABC will have confidentiality agreements for you to sign, and that you will be signing contracts with each client you onboard. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements, and assure them that you are honest and full of integrity.", "\"I have signed NDA's and confidentiality agreements with my former employers as well as every client. As a professional in the wealth management industry, I also understand the importance of asking my clients to sign the same, so that everyone is protected. I hold myself accountable to confidentiality agreements and take pride in my honest character.\"", "\"Before starting my internship, I was asked to sign a confidentiality agreement, which made complete sense to me considering the information I was privy to throughout that time. Discretion has never been an issue for me, and I am happy to comply with any matters of confidence on behalf of Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you have a personal or professional mission statement?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you have a personal motto or mantra that you live and work by. In business, especially when working in a sensitive industry such as finance and wealth management, this is an important question to ponder. Think of this question as addressing your credibility statement, ensuring you come across as trustworthy and honest, to your clients, peers, and management.", "\"I work to better the lives of each client. That is my mission. I want my clients to feel that I care about their financial wellness and their long-term financial plan. They should always know and be able to see that I will do what it takes to ensure they are comfortable in the long-term.\"", "\"My mission statement is to remain humble as I grow my career, and always look for opportunities to grow and learn. The more I know, the better position my clients will be in; however, it takes humility to admit there is always more to learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "Do you have any questions about this job, or working for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Remember; it is not a badge of honor to say that you have no questions. Many candidates feel that by saying they do not have questions, they are showing that they have researched the job and fully comprehend the requirements. The right response is quite the opposite, however! By asking an insightful question, you are showing the interviewer full engagement and interest. Be sure that your queries are not mundane or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a question that is easily answered by simple research. Dig a bit deeper and ask questions such as: \n\n- How has Company ABC embraced FinTech advancements this year? \n- What is your favorite part about working for Company ABC?\n- What is Company ABC biggest goal in the next 12 months? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in the wealth management industry over the next two years? \n- Is there anything from my resume, or our conversation, that I can clarify for you? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"I would like to ask if there is anything in my background on which you need clarification? Also, after discussing everything today, is there any particular reason why I would not be the best fit for this role with Company ABC?\"", "\"Thank you for asking! A couple of questions come to mind. What do you see as the biggest challenge Company ABC will be facing in the next 12 months? Also, what is your employee turnover rate for this exact role? Lastly, could you tell me about the retention plan you currently have in place?\""]}, {"topic": "Wealth+Management", "question": "What are your pay expectations for this role?", "answers": ["Since Company ABC is involved in the finance and wealth management industry, it would be no surprise if they were very upfront when it comes to discussing your pay expectations compared to their offering. \n\nIf you are newer to your career, the area, or this particular industry, and are unsure of what a fair ask may be, there are many reliable salary calculators available online. \n\nAvoid giving a wishy-washy answer. You want to be helpful to the interviewer while also sticking up for what you need, without pigeon-holing yourself too much. Answering this question well is a delicate balance.", "\"I currently earn around $90,000 per year including commission. I am looking for compensation aligned with the greater responsibilities of this particular role while leaving room for more commission-based opportunities and career growth. Could you share with me what Company ABC is offering, for this position?\"", "\"As I am new to my career and the wealth management industry, I am happy to negotiate my earnings based on your typical salary for this role. From my research, I see that the average junior financial advisor in the San Francisco area earns in the $55K range. Is this correct to say?\""]}]